SUBTITLES: K. FREGER, M. LEVIN, E. MASLENNIKOVA, Y. KARAVAN,
S. HOTYOV, L. NIESERENKO
-What the heck?!
What do you want?
You saw me pathetic, and I was the chairman of the Revolutionary Military
advice! A sacred deity! Demon!
- Your keys.
Thank you
Nice to meet you. -Wait. A...
What was it? -Your age it's time to know
such things. -What? No, hell! I'm talking about something else.
I saw him in the window, he was talking to himself.
Does he have hallucinations? Is he going crazy?
-Such as Leon do not go crazy.
They know how to see what we do not see, ordinary people.
And you know what? Today for a moment it seemed to me that I too ...
just about to see.
-So that's why you were not. This is not an accident.
- Hello, Jackson. What do you mean?
- You called Frieda, did not you? They told her to invite him to leave.
And they left to prevent them from interfering. He does not listen to you, but can listen
young mistress.
- Tell him - I'll destroy you.
-Now I understand why he loved you.
-In connection with the current situation of dual power Petrosoviet
does not consider it possible to support any initiatives
Provisional Government. All workers, soldiers and sailors
organizations are strictly enjoined: to sabotage any
orders of the Provisional Government and personally Kerensky A.F.
Chairman of the Petrograd Soviet Trotsky.
-Tell me, Lev Davidovich,
and the chairman of the Petrograd Soviet Trotsky
ever learn a typewriter? "Natasha, you know,
I and technology are incompatible things.
CALL TO THE DOOR Are we waiting for someone?
Zina, Nina! My girls! Oh, how straight you became girls!
Natasha, look who's here!
-Hello. -Leva, Seryozha, meet the sisters!
Hello my darling!
-Sasha, hello, my friend. -Hi.
-Let me help you. -What is your name? Lyova?
-Sereza. - Are you Seryozha?
- Let's show you the rooms! There.
Hello my dear!
- So, you will live with my mother, yes? -Yes. It's not far from here,
in two blocks of everything. -Yeah.
-Now, we'll see each other every day.
-Well, what about grandfather? I certainly did not want to let you go to Petrograd.
-Of course! Threatened us to lock. But we still insisted.
Zinka did this to him! -Of course. Here the revolution,
here life is boiling. And there alone sheep and goats and flour grind
from morning to evening. -Them more ... Mom from the link
released. So my grandfather did not have a chance.
Family reunification. -I am my grandfather never in my life
did not see...
- Do you want me to drive you tomorrow by car?
Do you have a car?
-Machine is not mine-official. But I could after the speech
arrange a tour of the city. And then we'll go and watch,
how to build bridges. Is it good? -Of course!
-Will we see the Winter Palace? -A winter, and Taurian.
And even Peterhof. Dress warmer. It's a pity that the fountains do not work.
- Stop talking, the cake is ready. - Here's the cake. Eat.
I'll go and work.
-Leva, Seryozha, the girls!
CHEERFUL CHILD'S LAUGHTER
SHOOTING
- Good morning, Frank. And your door was open.
-I need to wash.
And you are an interesting woman, Frida.
This is your free love ...
your pictures ...
primitivism, shocking ...
fixation on the theme of death ...
But most of all I'm not interested in knowing what?
Why are you here. -Do you know that Leon has become attached?
to you? -Nonsense. He is not attached to anyone.
People have always been for him the building material of history.
-You are not just a man to him. You are much more to him.
Judge
-What did you see there?
- See, it's the monarch.
In spring and summer these butterflies live only a few days.
And to those of them who are born in the autumn, God gives life in whole lengths
7 months, so that they flew to the warm regions, survived there the winter
and continued their lineage.
It's funny, is not it?
- And unfair.
-Leon knows he can not survive the winter, Frank.
"Why are you here, then?"
"To ask you to be a merciful judge, Frank."
- Hell, you're crazy.
-Who is not going to live long, rarely refuses
in earthly pleasures. -Require even after sex
talk about death? "Sex and death are not so little common.
Will you? -No, I do not like to stupefy the brain.
"It's not for the brain, Frank." This is for pain relief.
-For you, artists, everything around you is pain.
-In 18 years I had an accident. The bus in which I was traveling,
collided with a tram. My leg is broken in 11 places.
I had broken ribs, collarbone, a backbone in three places.
And the rail of that bus pulled me apart like a skewer,
coming out here, and broke all the bones of the pelvis.
It's stupid, is not it? To lose virginity by a bus rail.
It's not a game, Frank.
I'm 33, and almost half my life it hurts.
Physically. And I will never have children.
-Tell me about Trotsky better. -What for?
You yourself can ask him about anything.
-You asked me to be a merciful judge. The judge has the right
interrogate witnesses.
-Good. What do you want to know about?
How did we become lovers? -No. It does not interest me.
Tell me more about his children.
Did he really love them?
-Leon never was a good father. But this does not mean that he
did not worry about their children.
At least that part of it that was human.
ORCHESTRA PLAYS MARCH
-There were so many people, and everyone came to listen to Dad.
And do you remember that our grandfather took Chaliapin to Odessa? It seems to me, even there
people were less. - You are dirty, Ninka. Chaliapin - who is he?
So, the singer. And then the revolution!
-Fedya, you look, what stole!
- Comrade Chairman of the Petrograd Soviet, sign it urgently. Attachment for distribution
weapons to the workers of the Petrograd garrison. Kerensky forbade it,
and he immediately ordered Peter and Paul to disarm. What does it mean?
And the Cossacks will give out all their weapons.
-Content dual power! Oh, as Lenin does not have enough!
-Vladimir Ilyich prefers to sit in a safe house
and write letters. -How? And we heard,
that he is abroad.
-I'm sure Comrade Koba could tell where he is hiding
from prying eyes, Comrade Lenin.
-Dad!
-We are here! - Dad, we're here!
- My girls!
How do you like the revolution? Not scary? -Why are we to be afraid, when with us
Comrade Trotsky himself?
- Daddy, are we going to drive by car?
-And how! I promised. -Lev Davidovich, we are late.
-After the performance wait for me - and we'll go.
Yes.
-Who commands the minds, he commands the world. Today our minds
the revolution commands. A little bit more, brothers, sisters, a little more -
and the world will change forever!
CHORUS: Hurray!
-But what is the working mass watching at the moment?
It observes, firstly, the complete disorganization of the state,
and secondly, the incessant embezzlement of representatives of capital.
And in this situation, every worker has a full psychological right
say to myself: "If there is a disintegration, if the capitalists continue
rob, why should I remain silent? I will present a maximum of requirements
and I'll take what I can. "And this is the inevitable result of the state of things.
But is this the result to which we all aspired?
-No! -Golden power!
Power to the people! -Pretty! Have satiated on a throat!
Enough! -How can!..
- Believe me. On that day, at the time when the country will be at the head of the
such power in which each worker sees the expression of his own
he will say: "Yes, this power will not deceive me, it will not steal." And exactly
on this day, at this hour a new state will appear -
state of justice. -Hooray!
Unfortunately, there are still random people in the revolution.
The mediocrity that decides with its help is its own personal lowland
tasks. They tell us: "It's not time yet." They tell us:
"Everything will happen itself." I say "No". I am talking now...
or never ".
Yay!
-Park Kerensky!
"Trotsky, brother, have a drink with us!"
-Thank you. -Dad! Dad!
-I will not sign this. So tell him. Let yourself
copes. And no negotiations with Kerensky.
"Well said, Comrade Trotsky. I'll memorise.
-No time to talk to you, Comrade Koba. Someone is waiting for me.
-And with Lenin?
Do not be afraid, Comrade Trotsky. This is Comrade Lenin's personal guard.
-What kind of cheap spy fiction, Koba?
Where is Vladimir Ilyich? -Go.
(Fire)
(Yells)
-Where is Papa? He could not forget about us.
- Stop whining. He will definitely come back here, I know.
Nina!
-Bright, Vladimir Ilyich. Masking, personal guards. You definitely
read these newfangled spy novels.
-Your irony is inappropriate, Trotsky. It's because you did everything to make sure,
so that I was forced to start running, and myself slowly cleaned up
to the hands of power in my party. - It's not your party.
-Yes? It is interesting, but whose? Is it not yours?
-This is the party of the working people.
- Nina, stop! Nina!
Help! Nina!
No!
(Yells)
Nina! Nina!
-And you never thought, what then?
-Later? -Later.
Well, imagine: the revolution was over, the power passed into hands
the Bolshevik Party, in the country of ruin, war is inevitable.
- I'm not afraid of that.
-Yes, yes, I know. But how do you think, when the euphoria of the revolution passes,
How long will a Russian people-worshiper tolerate a Jewish ruler?
Here, Trotsky, you have two ways: either humble yourself and follow me,
or get out. There will be no compromise.
Show discretion now. And then stay with business.
Become ... the second person in the party.
Think about it
- And if I refuse?
-And then you will be swept away. Like Kerensky. Ugh!
For your life no one will give a penny to a broken one.
(Yells)
- You know ... I thought.
Go to hell, Comrade Lenin.
Zinochka, is something wrong?
-I just wanted to ask: did you ever think about us?
-Sorry ... Now such a moment, so many ...
everything is going on ... -You did not answer.
- I had a very important conversation.
- Important conversation! ..
While you had an important conversation, Nina was hardly trampled to death.
{}
-Frank, do you remember? ..
Be gentle with him. You are welcome.
I'll do my best.
Hello, Comrade Trotsky.
Do you know what the father feels when his children died?
It turns
in the animal,
able only to howl at the moon.
Then gradually this animal
out of you, and a man returns,
only already empty inside,
but still thinking.
And this is the worst thing, because when there are no thoughts,
you just howl. It is easier.
And then they appear,
obsessive suicidal thoughts.
Why were they born if they left before you?
For what purpose? Not just the same. It can not be just like that.
It eats you from the inside, it sounds in your head 24 hours a day ...
How the jukebox breaks sometimes and puts the same
plate in a circle. You try to stop, but it's impossible.
All the time the same melody. Same.
"I should hate you, but I do not feel hatred at all."
Only pity.
-You never had children. You do not even get to understand ...
what am I talking about...
The devil's a moralist. "It's a pity."
- I just wanted to ... - Would you like to regret it?
Go away, pity Sylvia.
She, poor thing, does not wait, that you will make her an offer,
While you are lying around from bed with Frida.
What, they thought, I do not know anything? Frida warned me,
that he is going to have breakfast with you. And believe me, I know perfectly well,
which means breakfast with Frida.
-Yes, you are right, I have no children.
And maybe it will not. But even I perfectly understand,
that there is nothing worse than children suffering for their father,
imagining himself a messiah.
And yes, I'm sorry for you. Pity is the only thing you have achieved
in the declining years.
Dont touch me! -Why are you doing this to me?
-I'm sorry, I completely broke my head because of this interview.
- You do not even come to me. I forgot when we were last
with you fell asleep.
-Silvia, I myself am not my last time. He is like the devil.
Every day I drink a drop of my soul. I no longer sleep at night.
I drink sleeping pills - one hell, I can not sleep until morning.
-I do not recognize you. You have changed.
I'm afraid of you. Let's go to me. Go.
Go. - I can not, Sylvia.
-Oh please. -I must finish this job.
-Can it be better to tell her about you and Frida?
You do not like Sylvia, but there's such an excuse to drop the ballast.
- Tell me about your ballast, Comrade Trotsky.
Why did you abandon power when it was already in your hands?
-Why do you think so? I did not refuse anything.
-Lev Davidovich, Kamenev called, he said: you urgently collect
all here ... -Yes. We will do it today.
-What will we do?
-Revolution.
-Wait, Lenin said about the 27th, today only the 25th.
-We will do it today. Collect the sailors.
CASH
-I have nothing to please you. This is Spanish. The virus is new,
not yet studied. Mortality rate is 20%.
Lev Davidovich, listen, so it is impossible. There is no doubt,
you are the chairman of the Petrograd Soviet, but you can not force
we choose between you and Lenin. -Lenin ...
And where is he, your Lenin? A?
Where is he?
Damn it, huh? No, there is none.
Fiction. Oh, letters in the hands of the Georgian - that's all your Lenin.
And you continue to obey him blindly.
-Natalya Ivanovna, and when will dad come?
-I do not know, he's been spending the night in Petrosoviet.
-I'll go get him.
- Zin, wait!
-Natalya Ivanovna, I'll need a basin with cold water.
-And where are you going? -I will not let you go anywhere.
-Yes, now you are here, you are the leader. But Lenin created our party
and led us to what we possess. He led us for more than 10 years.
And how many are you in the Bolsheviks? -Polgoda.
-Polgoda.
- Either you join me today in history,
or you will be on the roadside tomorrow.
Choose.
Act according to plan. I must report every half hour.
STRESSED MUSIC
-Who are temporary here ?! Give up!
-Kerensky fled, the Provisional Government was arrested.
In some places they still resist, but ... -What losses?
-20 people. - Only twenty?
- You do not seem to be happy. -Yes, I'm glad, glad.
And how our Jew arrived from Dorogobuzh.
And his horse's not dumb.
He went to Lenin to torture: "What can I do with the horse?"
- Lev Davidovich, are you all right? -Zinoviev, you were never told,
that the expectation of happiness - this is the most real happiness?
-What? -When you live a dream, it gives strength,
great forces. And when you realize your dream, why live further?
Ah, Zinoviev? Did not say? -No.
-Dad! - What are you doing at such a time?
-Serozha is very sick, he has a Spanish woman.
-What?! -This is very bad. He can die.
The doctor said that the death rate is 20%.
It is clear.
I'll be back in two hours. Collect all, we must announce our victory.
What should we do with the filly?
Come on.
"What have you done, Trotsky?"
-This is called a "revolution," Vladimir Ilyich.
-It? This is not a revolution, it is a revolution! This is a fucking robbery.
bank! It's not America, dammit!
"Comrades, take the car, take my children home, then ..."
come back for me. -Will be done, Comrade Trotsky!
Please come home. -Home, home!
Yes, I made a coup. But you will all call it a revolution,
if you want to save face. You will need it.
You were right, Vladimir Ilyich. Russia never recognizes the leader of a Jew.
Never.
But the revolution must have a leader. The choice is yours.
-I almost forgot. You have a birthday today, Trotsky.
Congratulations!
Thank you
CROWD LIKE
- Comrades! Comrades!
Comrades! The workers 'and peasants' revolution, about the necessity of which
all the time the Bolsheviks said it was done!
CHORUS: Hurray!
-The word is given to Comrade Trotsky.
THE CROWD SCANDES: Trotsky! Trotsky!
Trotsky! Trotsky!
- Comrades! We have longed for this for many days.
And today our dream has come true.
The proletarian revolution won!
Yay!
"And the Bolshevik Party carried out this revolution!"
"The last time Vladimir Ilyich Lenin rarely visited the Petrograd Soviet.
He withdrew from his work.
So it may seem at first glance.
But this is not so, comrades.
The victory of the proletarian revolution is primarily our responsibility
this person. It was he who developed the plan for the revolution.
It was on his instructions that revolutionary sailors and soldiers acted.
This he led the uprising. Glory to Comrade Lenin,
leader of the Bolshevik Party!
Glory to Comrade Lenin!
Yay!
-Nata!
Natasha!
Have you heard this before? Damn it, we did! We won!
A? -Congratulations.
Happy birthday, honey.
-How is Seryozha?
-It's better. -What?
-You went to the dream for twenty years, like an obsessive ...
despising their principles and drowning all those who interfered with you, and then took
and so easily gave power to their sworn opponent?
Why?
-The truth-Jew really could not hold out in Russia
and months. For the sake of power, Lenin would split the party. And one by one
we were doomed. Power has never been an end in itself for me.
Next to Lenin, as part of the ruling party, I could continue to walk
to its true and only goal. -Yes, yes, I know.
To inflame the fire of the world revolution. -A, becoming the dictator of Russia, I would
bound his hands. The road to victory does not always mean forward.
We must be able to maneuver. Sometimes you need to stop and wait.
-Nonsense! You yourself do not disgust?
Look at yourself. It's not you, it's some demagogue, a weakling!
-And you do not have the intelligence to distinguish real politics from demagoguery.
-I do not believe you. You forced your family to suffer for the sake of revolution.
And then they took and abandoned this very revolution, frightened
responsibility! Your family suffered in vain. Your son could die,
not seeing his father, in vain! - He's already died.
They all died.
-Dad...
-So early?
What, is there an excuse?
- Here, a new frame was brought.
Here it is.
Sit down.
- Dad!
We still love you. You're our dad.
Come here,...
My children! ..