OVER THE SUBTITLES WORKED: K. FREGER, M.LEVIN, I.KIRIK, E.FIRSOVA
- It is everywhere - and in the glow of a fire, And in the dark, unexpected and close,
Then on the horse of the Hungarian hussar, And then with a gun Tyrolesky arrow.
This is Kolya verse, Gumilev. Do you know what?
-I have no idea. - About death.
They say that God gives each person a life as long as the thread length,
wrapped around the human heart.
-And I heard that there is no God. -And I said that you
chubby gestures? -Larissa, I'm absolutely now
not up to your poetry. Kappel took Simbirsk, from day to day
will take Kazan. He sweeps our troops, as if he plays in the towns.
- You already killed him? -I told you hundreds of times,
my revolutionary struggle takes place in a different way.
-Yes, you are a living manifesto. Clothes, gestures, manner of expression.
And even your eyes - you know perfectly well how they look good
on your tanned face. Only this is not a rally,
this is war. -So what?
-By the bullets do not remember the manifestos.
You appeal to reason, but your instincts are stronger.
What can be more terrible and stronger than the feelings of impending death?
Where he cries with a cryptic scream, Clocochet, grumbles and screams
Unbridled force of darkness, There the canopy of the archangel of the wing,
The road countless essence leads to the ruined Rome.
But if the February Rome falls And goads a harsh shout,
Be, merciful angel, to them And stand to them, demon merciless.
SPEAKS IN SPANISH
- Leo! We are here!
Lyova, have you forgotten to take your pills again? -All is well. Let's go to.
A monstrous heat. I just can not get used to it. Good afternoon, Sylvia.
- Hello, Lev Davidovich. -An extremely original
tradition. -A historic Mexican custom.
It is believed that on this day they pay homage to the deceased.
Frank!
This is my fiance Frank Jackson. I told you about him.
-Yes Yes. Very persistent young man.
- Ladies ... -Frank.
-Signor Trotsky. - Tell me, Jackson, that you
did not understand from our telephone conversation? It seems I clearly
made it clear that there will not be an interview. -Yes, the answer was quite unambiguous.
But I think that I can convince you.
- Convinced? Even my wife does not always get it.
"I would like to thank you, senor Trotsky." Your book saved my life
in Spain. As you can see, this fragment should have belonged to me.
-Why did you bring this book? You are a convinced Stalinist.
Or did you think that I would not bring you information about you?
"I really respect Comrade Stalin as an outstanding
statist, but that does not mean ... -Your Stalin is a mediocrity
outstanding, worthless.
-Yes, I do not just respect Comrade Stalin, I bow to him.
-Aha. -How before the great man,
the ideologist of communism. And you in every little miserable article defame
his name. You call Stalin bloodthirsty for his struggle
with the enemies of the revolution, and they themselves drove millions of people who were
not only were not your ideological opponents,
but did not understand politics at all. -Yes, I really doomed many
to death - and enemies, and their own soldiers. But there is one detail,
which distinguishes me and Koba. -Yes? Which one?
-He absolutely does not care about the idea. He only fosters his human
weakness, under the guise of ideology. Paranoia, love of power, greed.
In power, he is the same person that was before her. I had to stop
to be oneself, to disappear. Consciously.
I did it.
In the name of a great idea.
STUCKING IN THE DOOR. Sign.
It's all? -Voisk retreated to Sviyazhsk,
and, judging by the reports, their condition is extremely deplorable.
-The state of the troops is my concern, not yours. You are free, Sermuk.
yes
-I remember well in 1918. We suffered defeat after defeat. Ordinary
measures of influence did not help. The troops did not just retreat - they fled.
-Brats! Here, listen! Come closer! -Well, what are we, Russian people,
against the Russians to go under bullets? -Yes and in general, they say, not for long
remained to these Soviets! -Here! Pushcha they themselves, the Bolsheviks,
on Kappel go instead of us! -Yes!
-We admire! -And if the composition is not given,
take it for yourself! CROWD: Yes! Yes! Let's take!
- Come home! CROWD: Yes!
THE GUYS OF STEAM LOADING
-Soldies! Soldiers of the Red Army! Less than a year has passed
since you and I, holding hands,
threw off the yoke of despotism, class inequality
and the exploitation of man by man! But there are those,
who persistently want to make us slaves again.
They are there, on the other side of the front. Landowners, manufacturers,
White Army - they really do not like freedom,
which the Bolsheviks presented to the workers and peasants - you,
all those who had worked three shifts yesterday for three kopecks,
and today with a weapon in his hands he says to them: "No, we will not give up
you our freedom! No, we will not turn again into your
slaves! "I know each of you is ready to serve the cause
revolution, is ready to lay down his head for her.
Give me your hand, brother.
Give me, bold.
Here! Between me and them there is no difference.
There is nothing that could belong to me and could not
belong to him. Nothing!
Take it. Take-take. RIPOT IN THE CROWD
Take it. FROM CROWD: A good gift.
-When did you decide to abandon your pocket watch?
-This is not for me. -I will help.
-World, which we are building, - in this world all the good
will be common. Hooray! ALL: Hurray!
"But for our victory it is necessary that our enemies are afraid of us."
So that he could not even think back!
And how can he not think about it, if we give them a city
outside the city, if our soldiers of the revolution were today
panic and fear? Yesterday the soldiers of the 2nd Petrograd Regiment
left their positions on their own and fled.
Where is the commander and commissar of the regiment?
- Commander of the 2nd Petrograd Regiment Gneushev.
-Commissar of the 2nd Petrograd Regiment Panteleev.
-Take every tenth soldier out of order.
-Tenth.
Tenth.
-Lev Davidovich, these are workers, they recruited Vasilyevsky in printing houses.
They saw the rifles for the first time a week ago.
-Tenth.
Tenth.
-Do not be afraid. Many contemporaries will not understand you. They will condemn,
even called a Judas. But the future will justify you and exalt you.
Decimation.
-Tenth.
-Now, stand in the line.
Comrade Commissar, you, too, get on the job.
For the shameful betrayal of Soviet Russia, the revolutionary tribunal sentences
deserters of the 2 nd Petrograd Regiment ...
-That's it! -... their commander Gneushev
and Commissioner Panteleyev sentence to the highest penalty - shooting.
The sentence is to be carried out.
Perhaps now my actions seem too cruel to you,
but then I sought from the troops not just discipline - I sought,
if you will, the greatest manifestation of love. Yes, yes, you did not misinterpret -
love. The enemy was a force that was born only by death. I became that force,
which could execute, but could also be pardoned.
"You mean you wanted to become a second God for the soldiers?"
-The second one? No, Jackson, no. Look wider. I had to
oust him. God is a convention, nobody saw him. I stood with these
people on the same land, it was easier to believe in me.
And they believed. -Well, if they turned their
bayonets against you? -Yes, such an opportunity existed.
However, the soldiers acted differently - they raised the enemy's bayonets.
-I do not understand. -I also did not understand it before,
until he met a man who explained this science to me.
Beast!
We demand Trotsky! SCANDED "TROTSKY"
-Humble! Be silent!
SCANDED "TROTSKY"
Be silent! Be silent to all!
Demidov! Run after Nikolai! What are you standing there for Trotsky?
-All like the chain broke, the rogues. And most importantly, everything is as harmonious as a sentry
mechanism. "You're calmer, Demidov,
quieter. Who, you say, is there water troubling?
-Zhidok from the 17th chamber, Bronstein. -Political?
"Yes.
SCANDED "TROTSKY"
Open it.
What's making noise?
-We demand to immediately stop the practice of beating prisoners
overseers. We demand the provision of emergency medical care
our friend, Sivoronov. We demand to punish the guilty.
Besides ... -You ...
-... in the context of our requirements it does not matter.
-... You probably play chess. -In the context of our requirements ...
-Make a favor, do not refuse, one batch.
Around all mediocrity, there is no one to even train with
logical thinking, do not believe it.
-In the right.
Please, sit.
But you, Bronstein, are a phenomenon. By God, darling, a phenomenon.
For 27 years in Russian prisons I do not recall the case,
so that the Jewish brat could lead to the rebellion of the Russian matriarchs.
And you know, for what atrocities arrested Sivoronov, whom you
Were they defending? -And me, Mr. Trotsky ...
is not at all interested in what he was arrested for.
For whatsoever, he is still a man, has rights, and you oppress him.
And all the oppressed seek freedom and justice.
-You, the right word, you, Jews and revolutionaries, do not know
Russian people, but all the while trying to get it from someone
save and release. Russian people can not be liberated, otherwise inside
his soul will rise up such a darkness that will devour the whole world,
and the first - liberators. The Russian people can only be governed,
for his own good. -Even if it is so,
why beat? To beat a man who is already caught,
awaits trial with legal punishment? -And how else can people be managed?
-How? By personal example, leading to the ideals of justice.
-Are you blissful?
Yes, if it pierces you, with your kindness, to live for at least 5 more years,
you certainly will understand that you can only manage people ...
fear.
Fear is at the core of any order.
Better to beat one undeservedly, in front of everyone, rather than later
beat anyone who loses fear and chaos.
- Do not you think it's inhuman?
-Of course. I am in power.
It is impossible to decide the fate of people, remaining for them a man.
It is only now, by youth, you naively believe that the world
ready to follow you only out of sympathy with your utopian
dreams. But two years later the naive will pass,
and the thirst for power will remain. That's what I see in your eyes, Bronstein.
"Your words are beautiful, Mr. Trotsky, but they are refuted by all those,
that now occurs. And because of your chauvinistic nature
narrow-mindedness can not see it. Well, you beat Sivoronov,
to frighten others. So what? The opposite was achieved.
People have united and demand justice.
"So they do not demand more, do you hear?" -Prefer more, be still.
Do not be surprised then, when a wave of popular anger will sweep you away
and throw it where you belong and in the cesspool of history.
-Well, but how else?
Caesar, as they say, Caesar's.
And to us, the dogs are rotten ...
only to howl and ask for a bone.
Fate-with. In the 21st century, with the general roar of the jubilant crowd,
blouse, snout with a shoe knife in his hand, climb the stairs
to the wonderful face of the Sistine Madonna ...
and will undress this face in the name of universal equality and brotherhood.
You so-so imagine it? -No, you are so-so imagine
21st century. This is your, gendarme, worldview, which is capable of
only to distort the best. To all - in robes. Breathing and coughing
on command, to live by order - this is what you imagine.
-Yes about the 21st century - it's not me. This is Dostoevsky.
Are you also in a cesspool? ..
Yes, Mr. Bronstein ...
I was wrong in you. I thought that you have something real. But no, solid
oratory and posturing. Mat.
In his house!
GROM, NOISE RAIN
BELL BELL
- I am nobody and dissolved ...
In the square of light near the heavens ...
I died not condemned ...
And again he was resurrected.
And day is like night, and night is like eternity ...
And only faith in humanity
I'm not allowed to go insane.
-You can only manage people with fear.
SCANDED "TROTSKY"
-A day is like night, and night is like eternity ...
And only faith in humanity
I'm not allowed to go insane.
Dad!
Do not leave me!
Don't leave I beg you to come down
Dad!
- Leiba!
SEVERE BREATH
-Father? It's you?
- I, who else.
Well, Bronstein, is the lesson learned?
-Based.
I swear, I'll get out of here ...
and destroy all your foul world.
- Nothing will come of it. Because the scruffy world is in you.
Remember, Leiba.
I tell you this, Nikolai Trotsky, who can crush you
Right. Now!}
- Walk to the stove, warm up. -Thank you.
-Now, and the frost is now. Maybe you can fix the clothes better,
and then on the road, you will throw off the hooves. -Nothing, I'm used to it. What about the documents?
-Documents can be done efficiently, not a single bastard will be undermined.
You, the main thing, tell me which name to enter. Petrov or Stepanov?
"It is impossible to decide the fate of people, remaining for them a man."
-Trotsky. "It's me telling you,
Nikolai Trotsky. "My name is Trotsky.
"So you took the name of your jailer?"
- I did not just take it.
I ... immortalized her.
I, if you will, took off his skin and put it on,
as some hunters do. And, in fact, who is a hunter?
This monster, overpowered by another monster, no more.
In 1918 I was obliged to become the most terrible of monsters.
And he became it. -Then it justifies all that,
to which Comrade Stalin is compelled to go today.
-The monsters are divided into two categories. Some become them
for the sake of a super-goal, and others - simply because they like.
-Do you know what I just heard? Allegation
wounded lion, harboring resentment against a stronger opponent.
And yet it's Stalin, not you, he built a world that everyone dreamed of.
He did it, but you do not.
"My dear, it's time to drink the medicine." -Natasha, I do not want to. Today I am myself
I feel great. - Do not argue, please.
You know, it's useless. -You see, Jackson, not only
you do not recognize my leadership.
"I think your wife sees you as an ordinary person,
who needs to sleep, eat and drink medicine.
-You think so, Jackson.
I am sure that for her I am much more than an ordinary person.
While in Europe they talk, Russia demands real deeds. I drove through
in freight wagons 8000 miles to get here to you, to Europe,
a forge of revolutionary thought. And what do I see?
Revolutionary thought through and through smelt of apple strudel.
The newspaper Iskra writes the same thing all year round, the same thing!
How much can you dream of a helpless theory of revolution in a well-fed Europe?
You look like a gymnast, summoning the spirit of revolution to the saints.
And you believe that he will come! -Neslyanno!
"Comrade says the same thing. -Said it right!
-But not in Europe, but in Russia now the most striking contrast
Between the wealth of the rich and the poverty of the poor.
Throughout the country millions of brutalized disgruntled people,
and right now Russia needs a revolution,
otherwise the authorities will again start another war with Europe and write off on it
all troubles. -What he's carrying! Revolution is possible
only in an industrially developed country, only in Europe.
-Nonsense! Europe, in which live the well-fed, calm people,
can not lead - therefore, it always
will be driven. -Russia is a backward country.
-Yes, backward.
Zakostenelaya, spinning, burning in its own malice,
but this is power. This is an energy comparable to ocean energy
tides. I say to you: take this power,
tame, arm, and she will sweep away everything in its path.
"Bravo"
I have not been so cheerful for a long time. Your naivety may outweigh
only your stupidity. Farewell, child in a kosovorotke!
"It's only good, Comrade Plekhanov." You obviously stayed long in this cafe.
"Comrade Trotsky, allow me to introduce myself ..."
-I totally agree with you. Left to myself
The proletariat will limit itself to economic demands.
People between freedom and bread will always choose bread.
Please...
Lenin. - I know who you are.
If you really think so, why did not you support me?
- He has authority in the party.
Our quarrel will hurt the movement. And you with such outbursts
quickly burn out. "Is it better to smolder than you?"
I'm afraid I will not be forgiven. -Who?
-People. -Do you worry about the people?
-And you-about whom?
-I want to change the world.
What do people have to do with it? People are just a tool.
-In your hands. -And in yours.
And our task is to make them want a revolution, not bread.
-Well, and how to do this, if you constantly agree with Plekhanov?
-Georgy Valentinovich is also just a man.
-Is there an instrument? - Quickly learn.
And come to visit.
In a simple way, without ranks, in a friendly manner. -We are not friends with you.
Well?
bread is broken.
STOCK IN THE DOOR
"Yes."
-Good afternoon! Let me introduce myself,
Parvus Alexander Lvovich. -I know who you are.
-And what do you know about me? -You are the person who makes money
on everything, even on the revolution. In a word, an extremely slippery type.
-I came to congratulate you on one brilliant, but, unfortunately,
nothing changing speech. You are a wonderful speaker,
a great publicist, you are a man who, undoubtedly,
there are makings of a leader. So I came to offer you help.
-Thank you, I do not need.
-Do you think it's better to sit here?
Let's talk frankly. Plekhanov and Lenin are great people,
long leading the movement.
But, unfortunately, nothing happens.
-What are you driving at? -Direction needs a new leader.
And there is such a leader. A man who will light hearts, for which people will go
not only in coffee shops, but, if necessary, and with bayonets.
Such a leader is you, Lev. - No one knows me.
-Nonsense. Making people famous is my job.
I made Maxim Gorky. Now he is known throughout Europe.
-Gorky is a writer. I do not need such glory.
-Even as needed! Let's talk like this: let's say an actress -
if it is not known, it is of no use to anyone or interesting,
But as soon as she becomes a prima, everything is ready to be thrown at her feet:
money, jewels, if necessary, kingdoms ...
Yes, there were such precedents.
The revolutionary leader - as a prima, must come out and immediately take
viewers, supervise them. It's kind of ...
sex. No, this is sex itself.
-Well, I agree. And what is your interest?
-Money. I will make you the most influential revolutionary
modernity, I will earn money on your behalf.
As you can see, I do not hide anything. I do not build myself a monk,
I'm a merchant.
-I agree. Where do we start?
-Milayshy!
Courage! Courage, my friend! This house belongs to me. I'm sitting here
your colleagues, socialists. Please, I beg!
Of course, it's not the Metropol, and certainly not the Hilton, but still a house,
what-no, and housing. -Alexander Lvovich!
How good that I met you!
I would like to pay a fee for the next month.
-Natalya Ivanovna, how many times have I said that I will not accept money from you.
Uvolte-dismiss. -And I've told you many times,
that you can settle here for free these socialists,
and I do not intend to be a prizhivalko. Take it, or I'll eat it!
-As you wish.
Meet your new neighbor. Leon Trotsky.
Hello
- I was at one of your shows.
-Yeah. Well, how about you? -I did not like.
Nice to meet.
-I would be glad to hope something of you, but, alas, a hard nut to crack.
Oh, please! I beg!
The door can always be locked with a key.
From the ceiling does not flow.
Well? How are you?
- Quite, quite ... In any case, not a cellar.
-You are right, not a cellar.
-And how, you say, call this girl?
Well, you're not the first, you're not the last ... Natalia Sedova.
She is a man from a completely different society, Leo. Bohemia.
Theaters, exhibitions ... Other life, other ideals.
-I understood you.
-Good luck.
Plekhanov is a significant figure, but he is old. Put on it -
at least, unreasonable. I would bet on Lenin.
He is less clean in the choice of means.
-Lenin is too stubborn and obsessed with personal revenge,
and this can interfere with the main goal. There is another option.
-Yes? As far as I'm aware, in the Russian revolutionary movement
There are no more figures of the level of Plekhanov and Lenin.
-No. This newcomer is rapidly gaining credibility
in a revolutionary environment. If you invest in his upbringing ...
-We have little time. I do not know when the war will begin, but it will begin.
In the courtyard of the twentieth century, one cannon can not be defeated now.
We need a real lever to destabilize Russia.
Audi A6
On the other hand ... if we grow Trotsky from this
pocket revolutionist - an entertaining idea!
How much do you think you need money to ruin Russia?
through the revolution?
-It is always very difficult to answer this question.
I think that...
a billion marks will be enough.
"I have long wanted to ask you, Gelfand,
why did you choose the pseudonym Alexander Parvus?
Shy of your Jewishness?
-Good luck. -Bye.
-The more perfect the appearance of a person, the more demons
he has inside. And people, looking at the beautiful (wait),
want to see the hidden, low-lying, it attracts.
Not bad, not bad. -I think we risk losing ourselves
for all this tinsel. -In politics, nothing is accidental,
everything is important: what you say, how you say, how you look ...
Everything should be a single whole ... manifesto.
Remember about Natalie? -Emansip that did not like
my speech? -No, no, it's not that,
that you spoke badly. The thing is ... how can I tell you ...
all the Social Democrats look ugly,
Bad clothes. I understand, the most important thing is your inner world,
this is the most valuable. But internal aesthetics, not flavored by external
kind, like only the marginals.
Yes, I have good news for you.
A letter from some lady Sokolovskaya.
You seem to be married, you have two children ...
Do not you regret it?
-I never regret anything.
- "Hello, dear Lyova." For six months now, how are we managed in exile
without you. Glad you reached Europe safely. I always believed,
that at you it will turn out. Our girls grew up. Zina remembers you,
asks when the pope arrives. Nina, it seems, has finally stopped
to be ill. I do not know what else to add. I constantly remember our
last day".
-Whoa! - Hello!
-This is for you, documents.
Hide it ... Trotsky.
-How's Nina? -Sleep.
When?
-Today. Otherwise, it will not escape the taiga, it will.
"But it's not forever, is it?"
You will leave, but then we ... Will we be together?
-Yes. Oh sure.
-Well, get up! -A! A!
-Why lie down? IMPACT
Stand up, I said!
-Too late. I hope, answered all your questions?
Thank you.
-Here, Jackson ...
If you decide to continue ...
Come. From this day you are happy in this house.
-You will leave, but then we ... Will we be together?
I: Yes, of course.
-Sorry, Levushka? -Sorry ... Sasha.
-Dad! We're here, Dad! - Dad, do not leave me!
Dad! Dad!
- Leo ... are you alive?