SUBTITLES: O. KULAGIN, Y. KARAVAN, E. FIRSOVA
IN SPANISH: I must search you, señor Jackson. New rules.
"Yes, Senor Trotsky has finally agreed to security?"
- No one asked for his consent. We do not want Senor Trotsky
killed in our city and put us to ridicule.
Why do you need this?
-A common knife for papers.
- I'll keep it for myself. Take it when you leave.
-Good afternoon, Comrade Trotsky!
Do not you have anything else to entertain? -I worked in this chair since then,
as here moved. And as you have already understood, after yesterday's
I'm not going to give up either my ideas or my own
Habits, no matter how many killers you send here ... your idol.
-Can you call a carpenter better? He will do it better.
-And he refuses to come. Afraid that the infection will spill over
to his house. Ah, hell!
- Give me your hammer. Yes, do not be afraid, I know how to deal with it.
to be managed. -You are welcome.
-You are constantly calling Stalin a murderer. And you? Are you not the same
a bloodthirsty tyrant? How many victims are there in your account?
-The critical situation required critical measures.
The question is not the number of victims, but the fact that they are brought for what.
-The dead are always dead. -This is why you should think
about the living! They own the future. The death of the past fertilizes the present
and generates the future. All. -All losers justified tyrants
sacrifices made by great goals and by the fact that contemporaries
could not understand them. -If there was an opportunity to avoid
I did everything possible for this, sometimes
even to the detriment of himself.
- The Lord! Council of Workers' Deputies
Petersburg offers
to start a general strike. APPROVAL COUNTRIES
On January 9, we have already seen what your peaceful protest is worth.
Enough! Do you really think that your general strike will cope with their
bayonets? We must act radically. -What are you offering?
-That the only thing a normal man can and should offer is -
arm. Armed yourself, arm the workers. Urgently needed
deploy clandestine arms production. It is necessary to seize the printing press
and print leaflets calling for revolution. And then,
only then, we will be heard and will speak on equal terms.
-When you walk wide, Trotsky. So you can break your pants.
INNOVABLE AGES AGAINST THE TROTSKY
"Comrades, the path of armed insurrection is not our way."
If you still do not understand this, Trotsky, you better leave the Council.
INHOMOGENEOUS OBJECTS
-Why does it smell of sour cabbage everywhere, Dr. Gelfand?
-There smells like typographic paint. From the very childhood, I hate this smell.
-Good God, tell me that I did not in vain come to this accursed city!
"I'm afraid you have nothing to please, Herr Kobert." As a member of the St. Petersburg
The Soviet of Workers' Deputies declare that this is a gathering of cripples and impotents.
-I heard that your pet Trotsky appeared in the city.
-Yes, he is rapidly gaining credibility in the working environment.
But we're not going to step on the same rake?
-Do you know what the revolution did not have on January 9? Sacred sacrifice.
Togo, with whose name on their lips people would go overthrow the regime.
- Do you think that Trotsky will approach the role of such a victim?
-Why not? You yourself say, people love him.
He is young, hot, smart. "Why should the gendarmes kill Trotsky?"
Arrest and reference? As usual?
"Who told you that the gendarmes would kill him?"
"Do you want me to kill him?"
It's impossible. -How much do you want for this job?
Hold it. This is your 30 pieces of silver.
Hold, do not be afraid. We do all the dirty work ourselves.
Your task is to make in the shortest possible time so that in this city
every dog ​​knew about Trotsky. All the rest is not your business.
-Yes, we are so. It was necessary to enlist the support of the Council.
-The Council is a pitiful bone, which they left us to talk,
to bring the revolution to nothing. Until we take matters into our own hands,
nothing will be achieved. The revolution is like a woman:
showed weakness or indifference - and she will leave. Therefore, we need strength,
an armed worker is needed ...
-Our. Come on.
-Stand! Who are they?! Hands up to see!
Search.
-We're leaving.
Flyers:
-To arrest.
You fool!
-Walim!
-The entire circulation of leaflets was seized by gendarmes. One comrade was killed. Now
all printing houses will be guarded. -No trouble. We just started.
A month ago we did not have this. -You do not understand? Now Russia -
as an apothecary balance. On whether the workers will support us,
it depends which cup will outweigh.
We need thousands of leaflets, tens of thousands. We need a newspaper.
- Leo, look at me.
Look at me.
I fell in love with a man who does not fall for difficulties.
I'm not going to be disappointed. My man does not back down and does not give up.
He always wins. And you are my lion, and no one will stop you.
-I will not take money from the Germans. This is the logic of the victim.
They want to use me.
But you are not a victim, Trotsky, you are an aggressor.
"That's why I will not let anyone manipulate myself."
-Let's look at this from the other side. Where, if not in Germany,
will they catch the "flame of the Russian revolution"? They want to use you,
and you use them. Take money from them and at their own expense show
an example of a revolution by the German workers. -I see you principles
and have not acquired. -Principles hinder commerce.
Do you need a rostrum? I have everything - money, communications, newspaper,
which will provide you with this rostrum. Deal?
-I want you to know. You are deeply unpleasant to me.
-l'll outlive this. Tomorrow morning in the editorial office of our newspaper.
The proletariat must not only appeal to the revolution, but, above all,
himself to go to her. The revolution can not be appointed for a certain day, hour,
as a demonstration. No people have ever committed a revolution
on the team. But due to the inevitably growing catastrophe, it is necessary
already now determine the most successful positions, arm,
inspire masses with a revolutionary slogan, exercise them in combat
art, keep under arms, so that at the right moment
hit the entire line with alarm. The revolutionary proletarian mass
there is. It is necessary to have a one-time skill in the entire space of Russia
to bring this mass to the streets and unite with a common cry.
18 Toch
- Trainers Thomson and Khodashevich!
Clowns of Turov! ..
FOLK MUSIC
-Davno you were not visible, David Leontyevich.
-So not a boy, so that 30 miles to and fro ...
And now would not have come, and granddaughters asked them to show the city.
- I'm Petrushka! Do you have a millet seed?
-No. -I have.
- "Through the arming of the working class and revolutionary violence
to a just world of universal equality at the cost of the greatest
self-sacrifice. The blood of our best sons was bought by our motherland
my freedom. "-This only give me rifles.
-Well, are not you pleased, zhidyara? Harey did not come out?
-All, that's all. The old Jew leaves. -I'm asking you!
-Hey! Break off!
-Deda!
-You are my Zhidovochki, beauties ... Do not cry, do not cry.
Well, go to your uncle.
Go, sweetheart. He wants to see his grandfather!
Well look. Here is our grandfather. Yes? You want me not to beat my grandfather,
My fish? The girl wants. Well done.
Well ... Then ... Eat then.
Eat.
Eat, zhidovochka, beauty. Eat. Eat.
Eat. For the grandfather. More. I will not beat my grandfather back then.
Here. " Well done. You see, now nobody touches your grandfather.
-Come to me. Come to me.
GORKO CRYING
-What, are you okay, zhdyyara?
"No.
No!
-Zhidyara!
"No.
DOORBELL
-What else? -There ...
- Hello ... son.
- I know, David Leontyevich?
-Come on ...
... the dove.
- I'm not going either.
Let's go with my father and take a walk. -Now?
-Well, why not? At night the capital shows its true face.
You did not like my Natasha? -I did not come to her, but to you.
LOUDLE LAUGHTER BACK
You can not imagine what a terrible beast ...
-What? Go, go. -... you release to freedom.
This is a dark force, terrible. You do not have time to look back, as she
will swallow up everything and everyone, and then you yourself.
- Father, well, do not, you do not understand anything about it. The future is ours.
And it's not as dark as it seems to you.
"Damn it, I'm your father!" Do not dare with me as ... with these of your own.
Do not kindle a fire, son, it's a hell fire, diabolical.
Do not inflate it. -You know, I do not believe
neither in God, nor in the devil. The course of history can not be stopped.
Impossible. - They almost killed your daughter,
and you want to give them weapons. -I'm sorry you had to
it's to survive ... -You wake up, Leiba! Look Back
around! This is your new world - he is all this and will never be another.
Do you want to sacrifice your children for these bastards?
-Yes. I will sacrifice them. And I will sacrifice my wife. And you. And myself.
Polmira prayed to the one who gave his life for their sins,
but they themselves are not able to sacrifice a fraction of their philistine happiness.
And I'm ready. I can. I can. Clear?
-You are not human, Leiba. You...
... you are not my son anymore. I ... curse you.
-You finally said it out loud. You cursed me back then,
when I left the gymnasium, right? You never believed in me.
And I'll prove to you that I'm right! And no one will stop me.
-I do not even know what to say. It is one thing to consider construction
material history of other people's lives. It's immoral, but at least explainable.
But be prepared to knowingly sacrifice one's own
relatives, family ...
-Aperitif. -And if you were offered to head
The Soviet Union in exchange for the life of Natalia Ivanovna?
-Natalya Ivanovna would be the first to offer such a choice.
Oh, my God, do not look at me like that, Frank. On this way, I lost
two children. The worst thing has happened to me already.
We have one more problem, Lev. -What?
-The cook refuses to go to work.
-So ... Let me guess. Infectiousness - violence?
-Yeah. -Clear.
The aperitif is transferred. Frank, do you know how to score rabbits?
-It was not necessary. -And I was taught in childhood.
My father taught me. Come with me. If you are not afraid of blood.
-This strike should grow into something more.
-Yes, but the masses are not ready yet. We just started rocking the boat.
And then, the weapon ... Without it, you yourself understand ...
"Damn your boat and your people!" The economy of Europe is bursting at the seams.
Including Germany. We require urgent action.
If something goes wrong, I promise you that our
cooperation is immediately recognized by your revolutionary friends.
Stop it!
{}
-I say "No". No, I will not lead the people now at bayonets.
We have just brought a call for weapons to the workers.
-Hell! The Universal Strike. Another reason to withdraw at one time
in one place such an amount of embittered people we have
may not be. -You know how much you can make
illegally, for one night shift at the Putilov factory?
Three. Only three, Parvus, one of which (at best) will be
shoot. It's a drop in the ocean. We need time.
-People's anger - a resource exhausted, Lev Davidovich. It ends,
melts, as well as the generosity of my patrons.
-You know what? Go to hell with your patrons.
So tell them.
-I'm not restful. I'm always afraid for you. Stupid?
-You knew what kind of life I was living. -It's not about you.
I do not believe Parvus.
-This is normal. No one believes him. -Yes. But the paradox is that he is right.
If I see it, then others - even more so. The revolution will either come to naught,
or it will be headed by scoundrels and businessmen like Parvus.
I'm afraid to tell you this, but ...
- What is "but"?
- Do not give it to her.
This is your revolution.
-What? What happened to you?
-Nothing. I'm just tired.
STRONG VOMITING
-So, come on, buddy. Today it's your turn.
-Before, I do not understand why you started the conversation
about the year 1905. That revolution you mediocre lost.
Justify the subsequent victims?
- I've lost, yes. And this was the right decision. Painful, humiliating,
but the only correct one.
Then, in 1905, I was between a hammer and an anvil.
One force craved my death physical, the other was smarter -
accordingly, more terrible. Allow.
-My generals pull hair from each other, arguing about what to do
with these fucking revolutionaries.
Some shout: "Pour the country in blood," others propose to negotiate,
they say, the economy will not survive slaughter. While they argue, the humble governor
Saratov managed to curb the revolutionary mood in his entrusted care
city. -For me it is an honor to serve the Fatherland,
Your Majesty. -It is probable, you know what,
that is unknown to my generals, Lord Stolypin.
Share the recipe? -Good whip, if it's wiped with the mind.
Here Alexander Nevsky, for example, did not attack the enemy, but allowed
Teutons themselves get out on the weak ice. And they went to the bottom under the weight
their armor. -I invited you here,
Petr Arkadevich, not in order to speak in riddles.
"I beg your pardon, Your Majesty." I wanted to say that with the rebels,
in my opinion, it is necessary to act in the same way as Nevsky
entered with the Teutons: let them act as they want.
Do not shoot them like January 9, but force them to shed their own blood.
It will forever compromise the revolution and its leaders
in the eyes of the people.
"And if they do not want to shed blood?"
-On this occasion in their crowd there will always be our people dressed up
in the workers. They will open fire on the troops, thereby force
soldiers to retaliatory actions. All the blame for the spilled blood will fall down
on the revolutionaries, and not on the courtyard, Your Majesty.
-All a strike!
All for a manifestation!
Let the one who is afraid hide!
- Comrades! The laws of criminal power are criminal laws.
-Correctly! -The culprit can not and will not be
dictate to us how to live! -No! Will not be!
- Let them hear your voice ... - Yes!
-... See your power! -Yes!
- Let them tremble with fear! -Yes!
-All on the manifesto!
CROWN CROWD
It has begun ...
Report back to the emperor.
It is urgently necessary to convene a meeting in the government.
So our turn came, Sergey Sergeevich.
Act decisively, but without too much publicity.
- Grow up!
Live, live!
Go.
-You're scared?
-Late for fear. There is no way back.
-And I'm afraid.
I'm afraid to see for the first time how people die.
-Do not be afraid of death. Especially when she ...
is justified by history.
In any case, after this day, the world will never be the same.
-Yes I know. Our children will live in a different world.
I would not want it to start with blood.
"Natasha, I think you'd better leave town." Just in case.
- I'm not going anywhere. And no matter what happens, I'll stay close
with you. -Nata!
- Leo, do not even start. You know that yours does not work for me
oratory.
In addition, we agreed that I decide everything on my own.
THE CROWD SCANDING THE SLOGANS
-The power of the fucking factory owners and politicians!
CROWD: Out! Down with!
"Long live the power of the workers!" "Long live the power of the workers!"
-Ise the forged gendarme's forged boot from the chest of the working people!
-We'll! Skin!
-Nahans ahead of time do not shine.
Puso to draw in. Do not sniff with your eyes, otherwise this brother will see you in a moment.
And the main thing is to shoot no sooner than they reach the square.
CROWD: Skin! Skin!
- Feel, Trotsky? It's your day! Your story, your revolution!
GERMAN: Do not rush. He must die at the maximum of witnesses.
Beware of the tsarist police.
-Trotsky, why did we stop? Just do not say,
that you were frightened.
- There will be a massacre. - Hell with him! You yourself wanted it.
You achieved this. Do you stop at the moment when
before the revolution is one step left? Trotsky!
"Let Trotsky say!"
CROWD: Trotsky! Trotsky!
The phone rings.
-The manifestation came to the Palace Square.
-Take care of Trotsky.
No hair should fall from his head.
Check everything again, especially lofts and roofs.
CROWD: Trotsky! Trotsky!
CROWD SHRINKS
- Comrades! We came to the ruling gang on the chest!
They promised us freedom, electoral rights,
legislative power. And where, where is all this?
Is there faith after that? CROWD: No!
-Nicholas II began his reign with the fact that he thanked
grenadiers for the murder of Yaroslavl workers. Such as you.
And now he made Bloody Sunday himself.
For him, Russia is a street girl, with whom one can do everything
for insignificant handouts. Is there faith after that?
CROWD: No! No!
- Look around! Has anything changed since yesterday?
CROWD: No!
-Did the gate of prisons open? -No!
-We still hear moaning and gnashing of teeth due to these
damned walls! Have our brothers returned from their exile to their homes?
"No.
-Nikolay II and his gold-rutted singers consider themselves
salt of the earth, and you - obtuse obedient cattle, gears of their full,
littered with the blessings of life.
But no, they are wrong!
It's you - the salt of the earth!
-Yes! Hooray!
-To arrest!
-Why did you stop talking? Continue!
-Now they want us to go with our bare hands
on their bayonets!
They want to repeat Bloody Sunday again, drown our
revolution in her own blood.
But this will not happen!
Our life belongs to us and only to us!
And we will not give it away for snuff tobacco!
We will choose another way!
And they, I tell you, they will pay very dearly
for the blood of our brothers.
"Yes."
- Comrades! We go home!
-What are you doing? What are you doing?!
-We are!
DISAPPOINTED GUL
-You made the right choice.
-Because of the bloodless?
-Because it's yours.
-The area is free. The crowd dispersed without a single shot.
-How did you split up? What the hell?
And Trotsky? -Well ... You yourself said that ...
- Arrest him immediately! -Listen!
-Immediately!
-Stopkin Stolypin ... -That you?
-Right, I'm uncomfortable every time to remind ...
-Do not bother. I spoke about you at the treasury. Come on,
you will write a check. -I hope now in St. Petersburg
with the German spy network over?
-I hope so.
Sorry, I have a lot to do.
And further. As soon as you get a check, get out of Russia.
It's been my honor...
-Excellent.
-Leave us out!
-Who are you?
-That, to whom, let's say, was instructed to restore order in the country.
- For that, you were ready to kill hundreds of people.
I wonder how you sleep at night?
- I'm not complaining about sleep.
You see, what's the matter ...
I'm ready to make sacrifices, but only when absolutely necessary.
But she was not there. - Stop lying.
Why then did you need to transfer troops to the city?
-It was necessary to be ready for any options.
I'm a pragmatist. The revolution will happen sooner or later.
I won the time.
And I will do everything possible to make the revolution bloodless.
-And here you miscalculated.
We will return and destroy you all.
-You do not understand one thing.
Any religion implicated in blood is a monster, which sooner or later
devours their own children. You think, feed him to us - and he will calm down?
No.
Think about it at leisure.
I was glad to get acquainted personally.
-Do not reflect like that, Jackson. It's not a rabbit anymore, it's a piece of meat.
Want some water? -Everything is fine. Let's get better
we will talk about you. -Let's.
-Why did you change your mind and did not go to the assault?
-In the world of the immaterial this is called the "sixth sense."
-Take it, Trotsky! You do not believe in God.
Why not admit the obvious - that you are banal coward.
-Well, here's the obvious.
In 1905 the people were not ready for a revolution. There was no weapon,
there was no clear program of action, there was no support for the majority.
Well and yes, yes, I was frightened.
No, not prison, not death. I was scared of the very same ones
useless victims, about which we have been talking with you since the morning.
-All these are just words. Facts say the opposite.
-Good. Here is one more fact.
If then I was killed, then there would be no revolution.
Do not you still understand that the revolution is me?
Why did you get up? - So the coal is over.
I also reported to Comrade Sermuk near Kalyazin.
- Where am I going to get the coal for you? It was said: stock up the wood.
-Where can I get some firewood? There is no forest. What will I be, stoking shops?
- Yes, even with your oak head! You wanted a tribunal, vrazhina?
"Collect people, Comrade Sermuk!"
Will you firewood.
"Comrade Sermux!"
-Herod!
What are you doing? Immediately my son is buried! Atheists!
There is no Christ for you! I'll kill you!
-Dow!
SHOES
- Finish the loading - and go. In two hours there should be
in Nikolaev. - Lev Davidovich!
With these what to do?
- Let's go, let's go.
Probably, it's hard to understand who never made sacrifices.
-You forgot that I fought. This science is familiar to me no worse than you.
Then why do not you eat?
Everything is simple. We need to eat, right?
For this, we killed a rabbit. That's all. This is a justified sacrifice.
-This is different! -Mm!
My life did not allow me to be like you.
- What does it mean - like me? -The young fool who craves
truth, but then he turns away when he sees her. Because the truth
cruel, and you - a young man who is still dreaming about something.
-I am tired of tolerating your insults. If it were not for your age,
I would ... - It's not an insult, it's true.
If you do not like it, you can go to hell and more
not to return.
-And you could not prove anything to me. Because in my world the truth is
really ... -Natasha, spend it.
-... and not what allows Leon Trotsky to find compromises
with his conscience. -Take it!
Father, why did you come? - Did not you call me?
"Yes, I ... wanted to talk."
- You have not changed much.
I remember when you were little, I dreamed that you would get
education, graduate from university, will become a respected person.
But you chose a different path, took yourself another name,
and now in your heart is completely empty.
This is bad. -I wanted to destroy the order,
built on the inequalities of people.
What's wrong with that? -And you asked people,
Do they need it or not? A?
He asked me?
Son, I worked all my life: growing bread, building our house.
And you dedicated your life to destruction.
-I wanted to build for all people ...
a world where justice and equality rule.
Sooner or later I will do it.
And people will see ... -What kind of people are they?
You're a Jew, Leiba. You'll never be your own for them.
"Our drunk came from Dorogobuzh, and his mare
nedyuzha. Piishov rabbi torture, sho with the mare to work.
And the rabbi replies: "And you are her slaughter-you sing Koninushki."
Eyes - no candles, guts - on books, and sho peed tail grew -
so that the entire Jewish censor goes. "
Farewell, Leiba.