SUBTITLES: K.FREGER, J.KARAVAN, S.THARTOV,
E.MASLENNIKOVA, L.NESTERENKO
STUCKING THE DOOR-Senor Jackson! Senhor Jackson!
You were asked to transfer.
Here you go.
SPEAKS IN SPANISH
Do you understand that there are places where a woman should not be? Even in the afternoon.
Come, I'll take you to my room. -No. You are an excellent lover
for everyone, but not for me. No one else can be
really good in bed after him. He had all this
the fucking world. To sleep with him is like injecting a drug directly into the brain.
It's like sleeping with God himself, you know?
- Then let me take you home. -What for? I feel good here.
Frank, you're very much alike with him. You do not love either
recognize defeat.
Pass it to him. And tell me ...
No, do not say anything. -I do not want to see him,
especially now. - Do it for me.
-Good. He called me today for a picnic.
"Jackson, my friend, you are not yourself today." Do not blame me for everyone
sins of men. Something happened?
-Nothing. -Ah.
-Today one person told me that I do not know how to admit defeats.
And that in this I look like you. -Aha! But I have nothing to admit.
I never had real defeats, although I repeatedly
stood on the edge. But I always managed to change the situation
in their favor. A clear example of this is the story on the armored train ...
"Listen, I do not care about your armored train, he's fed me!"
I understand that these are the best years of your life, the peak of power, but I would like
to hear about something else. "Now I recognize you, Frank."
Come on, come on. What are they accusing me of today?
-Brest world.
-This is ridiculous. People will not forgive you. Well, can not you not sign
this damned world?
-Nelzha. There is actually no army,
there is nobody to fight. We will not give the Germans what they want - they themselves are half the country
will conquer. -So, damn it,
make the soldier fight! -How do you not understand? ..
We ourselves have disintegrated the army. Now these soldiers can not be forced
fight. - Get out. Well, they can not
to force you. -Lenin only waits for that.
"Comrade Trotsky refused the archival mission!
Down with Comrade Trotsky! "No.
Well, everything, it's time.
PLAY "INTERNATIONAL"
Do not you mind?
-Because you are, you are the same Trotsky, the head of the current
government foreign affairs.
I guess we should drink ... for an acquaintance.
You are disingenuous about the third way. From the impasse in which you,
Bolsheviks, drove Russia, there are only two ways out - surrender and death.
-Vladimir Evstafievich, let's be frank. Is it not you, the royal
generals, you have so deeply moved your beloved Russia into the war?
-We did our duty. If it were not for yours, if I may say so,
revolutionary agitation ... Remember what you called the soldiers.
"Shoot the officers, fraternize with the enemy soldier!"
-Who is to blame, that our ideas were closer to the soldier?
-Your ideas turned the battle-worthy Russian army into a herd of cattle!
And you did it, Bolsheviks! -I'm going to remind you that, despite
on this, you still deign to accept the power of the Bolsheviks,
Comrade Skalon. So dull your ardor.
-I did not take your power, I accepted the will of Russia.
My motherland, she ...
as a beloved, but a mad woman - does not understand what she is doing.
But then he will understand, be horrified and regret.
But I will always be with her. And in joy and in sorrow.
-Bravo! Words of a true patriot. "Russia", "motherland" - all this
empty sound. Yesterday Courland was Russia, tomorrow it will be
Germany. Tell me that the Kurland is considered your fatherland, eh?
The world revolution will abolish the very concept of homeland. It is obsolete,
as well as everything, than you lived. No more your Russia, forget it.
-And what prevents me from shooting you right here and now?
At least I'll keep the officer's honor.
-Businessman?
-Children, comrades? ..
- Put it on the table.
-German government insists on the immediate signing of a peaceful
Treaty on the basis of self-determination of the peoples of Poland, Lithuania, Courland,
Estland and Livonia. As certificates of will
of these peoples, the German government considers applications
the governments of Poland, Lithuania, Courland, Estland and Livland,
signed in November and December this year.
-Lithland also departs the German Empire?
-People of Poland expresses their desire to join Germany? Rave!
-Pretty! What kind of circus did you want us to show here? This is not the will
peoples. These pisulki at the price of a penny recorded under your dictation
puppet rulers of the occupied parts
Russian Empire! -Herr Scalon, you, as the former
the tsarist general, forgive forgetting: the Russian Empire
There are no more, but there are these ... Councils of Jewish deputies.
-How the People's Commissar for Foreign Affairs, I responsibly declare:
Soviet Russia is ready to sign an agreement. However, I would like
give a clearer status of Livonia.
-If this is the only problem, by the end of the week we will prepare
all the papers.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Trotsky.
-Praise me in the shortest possible time to arrange the production of propaganda leaflets
in German. Write about strikes and police officers
arbitrariness. The revolution in Germany is a matter of time. Our task -
accelerate this time. In articles it is necessary to give an exhaustive
a picture of the state of affairs in Germany, which the German authorities, as they can,
they hide from their soldiers. Dot. I order the distribution of leaflets
half a million copies on all fronts, where the Russian soldiers
come into contact with the German ones. Dot. People's Commissar for Foreign Affairs Trotsky.
- Do you think his plan will work? -Maybe.
- And will you let him do this? After all, in this case, he will become the savior of Russia.
-Koba, it seems to me that the fate of Comrade Trotsky has been worrying you of late
more than the fate of the revolution itself.
- Bessonnay night, Mr. Hoffmann?
Well, it's time to discuss your separate peace with Ukraine.
-What Ukraine? What does Ukraine have to do with it? -Well, how.
You have concluded a separate peace with part of Russia. Under it subscribed
illegitimate government.
-Do you fool me?
- We will continue, when Mr. Hoffman will clean his shoes and remember the rules
diplomatic etiquette.
-The Soviets defiantly delay the time. This can no longer be tolerated.
I propose today to advance to Grodno and ...
"Are you an idiot, Hoffmann?" What war? What is Grodno? In our country
revolution! Do you at least understand this?
-What did you decide, my Kaiser?
The account goes to the clock.
-Rose on the rebels the army and allow to shoot at the defeat.
-When I go to the signing of the contract, I happily report:
The attempt of the revolution in Germany failed. General strike
terminated. The military factories are working again. By direct instruction
Emperor Wilhelm II we are in the ultimate form
We demand that Russia sign a peace agreement within 24 hours.
In paragraph five, the following changes were made. Russia undertakes
immediately complete demobilization of his army,
including the military units that were created by her current
government. In addition, Russia should withdraw its military vessels
into Russian ports and leave them there before the signing of universal peace
or completely disarm them. Military vessels of states,
who continue to be at war with the countries of the Quadruple Union,
since they are in the sphere of Russian power, they are equated to Russian
military courts.
-What do you mean "do not sign"? Is it still war or peace?
-This is the third way - not peace and not war. Record it.
Urgent order of the People's Commissar for Foreign Affairs Trotsky. Immediately remove all
troops from positions. -Yes, he's crazy, gentlemen!
-If the war was ever waged in self-defense, it had long since ceased to exist
be one for both sides. -I told you, he's crazy!
You trusted the madman, gentlemen! He's gone crazy! Stop it!
-Hopeful! - He's a traitor! Arms!
This is madness.
"Are you definitely going to go, gentlemen?" -Performed.
-I spoke to the Germans. They guarantee safe haven for all those who are not connected
with the Bolsheviks. -I can not with the Germans.
I do not understand how you decided to do this, Vasily Mikhailovich.
-Vladimir Evstafievich ... General Skalon, are you all right?
-Do not worry, gentlemen.
-Skalon, are you going? -I am now, Alexander Alexandrovich.
-I can not help noticing that this poor fellow had every reason to hate you.
You lied about the fact that Russia did not have the resources to continue
war. They were, just were in opposition to the Soviets.
-And who is it? -The same Cossacks.
-Well, of course. Where without them? -Take it, Lev Davidovich. You had
the opportunity to discourage strife and rally with the internal enemy
in the face of an external enemy. Especially Germany was already exhausted
and was on the brink of defeat. -Conclude a similar union,
this would mean that the new world we are building is not capable of
exist without the traditional pillars of the old world.
-However it would be possible to preserve a great state, and hate you
Stalin would not have had to struggle so hard to get Finland back,
The Baltic States and Galicia. You preferred to bend under the German, and your pride
cost ... -Thy.
-What? -T-sh-sh.
Do you know how the natives call this place?
Alla del Cododrilo - Crocodile whirlpool.
Here.
Jackson, do not move. Do not move!
Jackson, you attract the attention of predators. Do not move.
-You're crazy! -I am German. Imagine that I'm German.
Well, what will you do? Wait, when they eat you here?
Or use the outstretched hand of help? A?
You would now see your eyes full of hatred and horror
Simultaneously. I deceived you, there are no crocodiles. Get out.
I want you to understand one simple thing. I was knocked down many times
and threw them into the pool. It does not matter. It is important that every time I get up
and swam out. And the Brest peace as a result was forced to
to sign Lenin. Like this.
I will call things by their proper names.
Negotiations with Germany failed, in connection with which I officially
I resign from myself the People's Commissar for Foreign Affairs.
"Simply put, it's called" washing your hands. "
"I'm not going to wash my hands, Vladimir Ilyich. From what happened
we all must learn a lesson.
The country can no longer exist without a strong, disciplined,
ready for military operations. "Do not leave the topic, Comrade Trotsky."
-I am not going to absolve myself of the responsibility for failure
negotiations, but if we had a capable army, no one
I would not dare to dictate to us any conditions. Proceeding from the aforesaid,
I ask you to entrust me with the duty of the Commander-in-Chief
and the task of creating a new Red Army.
-You could not cope with the signing of a peace treaty
and want to cope with the war? -If someone from the audience wants to
take responsibility for the restoration of the army, I ask.
-In the meeting, a break is announced.
I hope you are aware, Lev Davidovich, that if you
fail also this time ... -I understand perfectly, in this connection
I have one condition.
-Condition? -Yes.
The key posts in the new Red Army must be ...
specialists of the tsarist army.
They are professionals.
And true patriots. -Do you offer to give again power
in the army to the royal officers? -Exactly. And issue an open order.
In case of treason of the tsar's officer, his family is subject to execution.
-Nonsense! It is not for this that we have been preparing a class revolution for years,
To submit to the same satraps, dressed in our form.
-I will support you.
Take action.
-Where did you get such good fellows, Comrade Sermuk?
-You yourself said, Lev Davidovich, the revolution should not only
to terrify, but also to delight. -Allow me to introduce,
Lev Davidovich. Larissa Reisner. My wife.
It was seconded here by a military correspondent.
-I remember. I read your wicked essay about me.
-I must apologize for that article. Larissa is a poet. She was fond of
anarchism and still can not get rid of maximalism
in their articles and publications. -You do not need to excuse yourself,
Comrade Raskolnikov.
Think better about how you will create the Volga Flotilla.
Ok?
-With cars!
Play "Whirlwinds of wicked war against us"
"Well, Lev Davidovich, now everything depends on you." The fate of the Russian
and the world revolution is in your hands. Without exaggeration, I say.
-Koba, you're going to the front, too? -I do not have such a beautiful shape,
as you do, Comrade Trotsky. But we both will do everything
for our victory, right?
-Well, where did you get to? - Daddy, give it to everyone there!
Mandatory
- Dad, you will not be killed? -How will they kill me? Look,
what armor I have. Not yet invented such a cannon to pierce it.
Help your mother.
I'll be back!
-Do, what should, Lev.
THE GUYS OF STEAM LOADING
-Sometimes, Dad!
"The telegraph has just brought bad news: Kazan has fallen.
So, if there is no miracle, the young Soviet Republic
suffocated without bread and oil. For the most part the Red Army disintegrated,
whole shelves are deserting.
There is a premonition of a catastrophe in the air, which is why I feel so desperate
live and feel. "
-Text start should be removed. For the future - no mention
about defeat, no matter what happens. The situation of the Red Army at the front
firmly. Success is on our side. Our valiant troops are squeezing
gangs of the enemy, and the European workers are about to drop the yoke of the world
of capital. - Lev Davidovich!
-Yes. -Come on.
-You clear? -Everything is clear, Lev Davidovich.
"I'm afraid you can not go any further, Comrade Pre-Revolutionary Council."
Kappel broke into the rear, cut the branch, goes here.
They know that you are here. Back too there is no way. There troops Komucha.
-How much time do we have? -Not more than an hour.
You can walk down the river. We expose one company to the barrage,
with the rest we will try to move to Boguchaevsk.
-I came to ...
to stop the retreat.
If I now escape, it completely demoralizes the army.
-Stay, die.
"Death is not the main thing." It is more important how to die.
If I die fighting, it will be easier for my successor.
"But we're not going to die with you."
-Then hand over the weapon.
Arrested. Both.
Now
Soldiers obey us.
{}
What are you going to do next?
Are you deserting?
Dissolve the soldier, and where are you going?
To Kappel?
They will receive you there. In the chain - and on the front line.
They really do not like defectors.
One way or another, we will have to fight.
And then perish. It's a question of time.
WEAPON 1
on the table!
To the guardhouse of both.
No. In the chain to the soldiers.
The weapons must be dispatched immediately before the battle.
Take it away.
I advise you to change your clothes.
In something appropriate situation.
-Patrons and grenades are enough. The problem with people.
White is three times more.
Samokatchiki will guard the passage from the train to the river in case ...
-Stop off! All in the system. Everyone to one. Samokatchikov,
stenographers, cooks - all!
- Lev Davidovich, you have already been seen at the front, you will already be spoken about.
Perhaps, we will carry out the evacuation of the command?
-I did not say clearly? All in the system! Running.
yes
-Stock!
- Lev Davidovich, our only chance is defense.
-They think so too, so they will not wait for us.
Our only chance is a victory.
They think we are afraid. But we sweep them, we are reversible
Their own weapons against them themselves, if we do what we have from them
no one is waiting. We will attack ourselves.
I, too, am afraid of death, like all of us. But I'll go there to survive.
And if I'm fated to die, I'll die in battle for what I believe in.
-Step the march!
BACK
- Lev Davidovich, our troops are retreating.
-Here! Here!
-Well, stand!
Stand! Where?!
Forward went! Attack!
Soldiers, listen to me! We have already won, there is only one step left!
Forward! Shoot them, fuck you!
Attack, your mother!
Well done! Well done!
How nice!
VOICES: Hooray! Hooray!
-Hush hush. Lie down. You can not get up, you are injured.
-We won? -Yes. The reinforcements came up,
and Kappel was dropped.
I did not think you could do that. -Sit in the saddle? I grew up in a village,
I love horses ... -And swear. You have them all so winged
mat. So now soldiers can fully consider
your father - after what you said about their mothers.
-I had to dominate, and sexual power is the main force
and the progenitor of power. - Did you read Freud?
-It was. STOCK IN THE DOOR
"Comrade Trotsky, the men are waiting."
CHORUS: Hurray! Hooray!
- "If any part willfully leave positions,
The commissar and the commander of the unit will be shot first.
Next - every tenth fighter.
In case of desertion, every fifth person will be shot.
Courageous and brave soldiers will be put on command posts.
Cowards, self-seekers, traitors will not leave the bullet.
Death or victory. Trotsky. "
STOCK IN THE DOOR
- Comrade Trotsky, Raskolnikov.
-Lev Davidovich, Kazan is taken. The Red Army passed into a decisive
offensive along the whole front.
-Thank you, you're free.
Sylvia, your fiance scared all the crocodiles around.
You can not be afraid of anything, you will follow him like a stone wall.
-All the amazing ability to not admit defeat,
self-satisfied with victories. Where is your praised objectivity?
-Objectivity is simple, Jackson. Everything that does not kill us does
stronger. Still, Nietzsche was right. -Nietzsche finished his life in the shelter
for the mentally ill. Do you want to finish like him? You are welcome,
live in a fantasy world. -Normal person is not able to
to turn the world upside down, to organize two revolutions and, at the same time,
stay alive.
Look at me, Jackson, I'm alive. -True?
-Yes. -You are 60 years old. You are an old man, exiled
on the edge of the world, from where you are trying to fight the greatest politician
modernity by writing memoirs that no one ever
will not read, because it's the memoirs of the defeated. And all because,
that you do not know how and refuse to admit defeat. You think,
are you still on horseback on your damned armored train?
Yes it's just ridiculous!
Then why do I laugh alone from the two of us?
Boo Boo Boo. A bad hour is already bu-bu-bu. -I had to give this to you.
in the morning, but ... -But I distracted you with my walk.
I understand, I understand.
"My dear, beloved Leo, you are a man of action." I too.
We do not have much time to live, and especially to you. We are both
understand. I have money, and I do not see any more reason to stay here.
Why do we, two loners, almost dead, hide, live in prisons
current lives? Let's leave and create a new one. Draw the remainder
days as ordinary people - by the sea, in love and bliss.
I'll wait for you in our bar. If you do not come, I'll understand.
I'll try to understand. But with you or without you, tomorrow I'm leaving.
Yours F. "
-Why are you back? She must be waiting for you.
-You see, Jackson, having left with Frida, I would admit that my former life
is over and I will not be able to do anything else in it.
Hell no.
Hell no!
Do you understand me?
- Lev Davidovich ... - Comrade Pre-Revolutionary Council,
Well, you did not warn? We would have prepared here.
-Care your people out.
-What for? -We will have
confidential conversation.
Comrade Voroshilov, are you in the same decisive battle?
140 Let's go!
-I did not ask you to sit down!
And put yourself in order when talking to the chairman
Revolutionary Military Council.
I have one question for you. Are you going to sabotage my orders?
-I obey those orders that I consider necessary.
-In that case, you're under arrest. Going to Moscow.
-Here my people are everywhere. You will be wiped out in powder.
-Your truth is yours.
We will execute here.
-T-Comrade Trotsky, I simply carried out the order.
Whose order? -Stalina.
- Stalin? -Yes.
-You are the commander of the front. Stalin is seconded to you
just as the head of the food part.
Do you follow the orders of the quartermaster?
-He is the hero of the revolution, a member of the Council of People's Commissars.
-You heard? Koba is now the hero of the revolution. Find and bring
to me this hero. This - under arrest.
"Lev Davidovich, will you?" -Yes.
-Progress. Stand still.
-I'm going to put out the light, Comrade Trotsky.
We are bombed from airplanes. - What else do you advise me?
Do not stand there, Koba, sit down. You know that thanks to
To the former tsarist military specialists, our army has finally begun
to win? With the exception of the front commanded by the hero
Revolution commissar Koba.
BOMBING
You hear me? -I already told you,
Comrade Trotsky ... It was not for that that we did the revolution to immediately lie down
under the former royal officers.
- Damn it, Koba! You were, as they were, and remain an ex, small
a criminal with the psychology of a shopkeeper. You do not understand a thing in politics,
nor in military strategy. Where are you going?
"Do not talk to me like that, Comrade Trotsky."
-I shoot you and Voroshilov from the front. Get out to Moscow.
And do not get in the way - I'll crush it.
BOMBING
-You know, Comrade Trotsky ...
you are right: in Moscow, I really can do more than here.
Just want to tell you at last one parable.
Once a proud eagle circled above the Caucasus mountains, and down in the lake
swam wild ducks. The eagle wanted to catch one of them and rushed
down, but the duck had time to dive into the water, and the eagle was left with nothing.
The eagle was very angry, flew high again to the very sun
and, folding his wings, threw himself down with a stone. "This time you will not leave
from me! "- shouted the eagle and also dived into the lake.
he began to choke and almost choked.
And the duck at that time quietly waved its wings and flew up.
"Look, an eagle, I'm fine myself
I feel in your sky, and you do not choke in my lake. "
- An instructive parable. Only I'm not an eagle, but a lion.
-So I'm not a duck either.
-You know, Koba, I also remembered the old parable.
Once the jackal came to the lion and said: "Let's fight".
The Lion grinned and turned away. And the jackal threatened him: "I'll tell everyone,
that the lion was frightened of me. "The lion yawned and replied:" Let the beasts condemn
me for cowardice, but they will not be scorned all my life for killing a jackal. "
-I'll tell you to turn off the light after all.
-Nata, you go, I'll work a little more.
-Did you ever think about how this will happen?
-No never.
I don't believe it.
You are too old to last long.
And too Trotsky to die in bed.
You think. Maybe, that's all you think about.
-Anyway, your way of avoiding responsibility is definitely not for me.
This is, rather, a manifestation of weakness. - In my case - maybe.
But in your position it would be an example of courage.
More courageous.
THE GOLDEN SHOES
I have not expected anything else from you.
I'm already dead. Like everything else you lived in, Trotsky.
Boo!