OVER THE SUBTITLES WORKED: K. FREGER, M. LEVIN, I. CIRIC, A. PRYAKH
-Lev, are you alive?
Lyova, where are you going? You are crazy?
What are you doing? Do you think you can win by making it easier for his mercenaries?
Trotsky has won, because he has beautifully left, right?
Hell no! Do not even hope to give up so easily, I will not give you
so take it and ... - Natasha! I'll give in when I start it
to be afraid. How do you not understand? He will win exactly on the day when
Leon Trotsky will stop walking where he wants, when he wants, where he wants.
-I heard the shots! - They did not hit me. ABOUT! ABOUT!
- Lev Davidovich, you better return. -Three! So so so...
- Lev Davidovich! - Leo, let's go home.
SPANISH: Señor, are you okay? -All is well. This I failed
the victim of an attempt.
I, as always, have not a single scratch.
-Yes, I'm sorry for the poor fellow. -Thank you.
"But, frankly, Trotsky, you always endangered
everyone who was near. -Only do not blame me for this.
It was not I who destroyed everyone who at least once shook my hand. I did not send
in the camp of thousands of innocent people. I do not send killers at night.
"Do you really think it's Stalin, yes?" Come on, Trotsky,
you flatter yourself. He has already defeated you for a long time - why should he now
to hunt you? You are not dangerous to him. "You do not understand anything, Jackson.
I will be dangerous to him for the rest of my life. Even if I do not say another word,
even if I humble myself. And I will not be humble. It's a boomerang, Jackson.
-What are you carrying? What boomerang?
-I created the Golem, and it will not stop until it destroys
own creator.
-Help!
-Take it.
ON-GEORGIAN: -What are you going to open? Finger?
L
-And all these gilded epaulettes with gray whiskers, and all
oak-headed chauvinists, wiping breeches in halls with stucco molding
and bas-reliefs, and all who press a working free thought,
we want to say one thing: do you really think that you can sleep peacefully?
No, we will come to you and give you a heavy kick in the ass!
Because we are stronger, we are younger and we are right! And the future is ours!
I tell you this, Leon Trotsky!
-Marxist? -S-with-sympathizer.
-Why do we work for the exploiters, comrade sympathizing?
- I have a mother, sister. I have one. -Ah, you bastard! Ugh!
-Mother, sister ... Family is a hindrance for a revolutionary.
We do not need sympathizers. We need supporters.
(shot)
Excellent, comrade-in-arms.
-Natalya, hello!
-Trotsky, do you watch me? -Fair? Yes. I want to ask you
one question.
Ask us.
-Do you want some fruit?
Ok.
Why do you think our meetings are boring?
-You are in Europe, Trotsky. Here museums, exhibitions, theaters, life beats the key.
And you sit in smoke-filled cafes and talk about changes.
How can you change a life you do not know and do not see?
-Yes, you are right. I do not know this life. I spent four years
in exile - there are no museums, no theaters. There many people
there is not even a future. They do not need to live, because they have no purpose.
And I want to give them this goal.
-Freude? -Yes.
-Surprisingly for a revolutionary. -You decided to study. This is now
fashionable. - Freud is busy.
His reasoning about sexuality is a bit shocking,
but the acuity of the mind is uncommon.
Goodbye.
Natasha
Well, suppose I want to see this other side of your life.
Me where to start? -Well, for example, tonight
I'm invited to a friend in the souare. You too can join.
-And what is soare? -Soviet Route.
-I'll think about it.
-Hey! Trotsky, but you know how to surprise. - My God, Natalie!
Finally, you're here too! How glad I am to see you.
- Good evening, Noel. Meet me: this is my friend Lev Trotsky.
-Good!
When he gets angry, he's even more beautiful. I'm just for a minute.
"Now look, you're ready to burn it."
-I'm ready. And not only him alone. All of them.
"You want to burn me, too, Trotsky?"
Be silent. I think I understand you. In you there lives a small deprived
a child who did not get something - mind, charm, will.
And for the sake of your petty resentment, you are ready to destroy all those who are better than you. So?
-You indulge your dirty vices, dooming other people to poverty
and humiliation. People who work hard to survive by themselves
and provide you with this foul polish. And you consider yourself better than them.
No, you are the children who hid here from real life.
But the storm is close. And when it hits you, you are very
wonder how long you managed to steal all these people.
I apologize. Apparently, I'm not created for this. I wish good
evenings all.
-Trogsky! Wait, wait!
- How's your ward? - Everything goes according to plan, Herr Kobert.
It is already being printed in newspapers. -Very good.
-I organized several speeches before the Socialist-Revolutionaries.
It is rapidly gaining popularity. But I have invested very much
much money. -It's not a problem.
I remind you, we do not have much time.
-A ... -Don't worry. It will still be.
What are you thinking of doing now? -I think that after the speech
at the congress he will become a real political figure.
-But without the patronage of Lenin, he is unlikely to be able to speak.
-About this, I also took care. -Very good.
- My father is a good man, but he is patriarchal.
So I did not want to live in his golden cage and wait for me
will be successfully married in order to give birth to a bunch of children, and fled -
to study in Europe. -My also refused to understand me.
It's funny, I'm an adult, and I, like a boy, want him
was proud of me and that he understood what I wanted.
-When acting contrary to the will of the parents, do we feel that we are betraying their love?
-May be. I know that I'm right, but I feel some kind of guilt in front of him.
A paradox!
Danger!
I'm not interrupting you, young people? -Not at all. We were at my friend's -
Lev asked to show him the real European life.
-ABOUT! And I have a surprise for you, Trotsky. Gift.
-What is it? -Mandate of the deputy of the congress in Brussels.
To me Lenin secretly said that he wants to make you a member
editorial board of the newspaper Iskra. -But I'm not ...
-I know nothing. Have a nice evening.
-The Lord, checking documents.
STRESSED MUSIC
-What are we sitting on? Document.
- "Wah-tang Mirh ... ... wali".
Mr. Officer! -Well, what have you got there?
Let's go.
-You generally attribute a lot to yourself in reverse. Already Stalin
ostensibly you have created. -Do you know Koba
was engaged only in exas. There was, as he put it, a laborer
revolution. Yours.
And from my articles he concluded that the decisive step would be
not for the well-fed intelligentsia, but for those like him,
people ready to shed blood. -And if Stalin is really
such a monster, as you say about it, how did you overlook it,
with your vaunted flair? -People with whom I then
communicated, were much more difficult.
I thought that the real danger would come from them.
-A, Lev. I did not expect you today. -Vladimir Ilyich, I read
your notes to my theses for the speech at the congress.
This is an obvious twitching. Plekhanov did not say that.
And even more so I did not write. - Well, to hell with the old donkey.
He did not say so, but he thinks so. And we will throw it aside.
-Then I would like to get acquainted with the theses of your speech.
- What's that for? -To be sure,
that you, like me, are not afraid to get your hands dirty.
- Would you like to lift the visor? Excuse me.
I am the head, and you are the tool. I say you are doing it.
Do not doubt, do not ask questions, do not make yourself offended
institute, but you do it. It is clear? -In that case, look for yourself.
Another weapon. But I have my own head.
What do you ..."
-Your life is in my hands! And, if I squeeze them, you will not be
neither as a person, nor as a politician. So you will do what
I ask. Otherwise, there will be no sincere speeches at the congresses,
nor walks in the parks.
Go away.
-It was not possible ...
... scare me. Failed. Moreover, I understood,
that you are afraid of me. I will become a new leader.
And people will follow me, not for you. And one day you crawl to me
with the proposal of union.
-You are charming.
-Hello, Natalia.
-Hello, Lev. So you like to watch from the outside?
-Well, some of these paintings will be seen by hundreds, maybe even thousands of spectators.
So, consider that I am one of the first.
-Do you condemn me? - You do not know me well, Natalia.
I am deeply convinced that no one has the right to point out to a woman,
how she should dispose of her body. All this is the morality of the past,
but I aspire to the future. -This is the future of which you
are you dreaming, immoral?
-The woman herself will decide,
who should get her body.
Her body, her feelings. And, if at full freedom of choice it is still
decides that it will belong to a single person ...
At least, it will be sincere, than all this false morals.
Well, besides, it's just beautiful. -Yes it is.
And that's why I'm here. And you are right - I decide who I will belong to.
-I remember you talked about sympathy for Freud.
You are welcome.
- Freud's lecture? -Yes.
- But it's in Vienna. -Yes. The train leaves in an hour.
If we hurry, we can make it.
- Will you soon have a congress?
-Quite right. Directly from Vienna, I'm going to Brussels. Want with me?
- To Brussels? -Yes.
-Boredom. STOCK IN THE DOOR
Yes.
-Madam, monsieur, checking passports.
Hristo ... Sama ... Som ... Samoksa ...
-Christo Samakalov.
We, the Bulgarians, have complicated surnames.
-Madam the Sedovaya. Monsieur Samako ...
"Do not even try." Good luck.
WHISPER: Trotsky!
Damn, what does this mean?
- Boring everyday life of an ordinary Social-Democrat.
-And nevertheless mediocre professors from academic communities
continue to assure us that,
that human behavior is controlled
reason, ideals and rules of conduct.
What nonsense. What an old stupidity. I insist that behavior
Man is governed by two institutions: the fear of death
and sexual attraction. -And money?
-Money, my friend, is the simplest, I would say, the most vulgar
reflection of sexual desire. -And dreams?
Do not we control dreams?
-It should upset you, young Fraulein, but your dreams are also nothing more than
a kind of sexual attraction.
Sex is any motivation for activity. The basis of actions
millionaire and a dreamer is the same as the basis for action
persistent lover ...
Prove your worth, master ...
... and cover.
For example, do you know what your satellite is dreaming about?
-On the world revolution. LAUGHTER IN THE ROOM
-Congratulations.
For example, in that dull gentleman, sexual attraction is expressed
in the money. And in order to master you, your male is ready
burn half the world! For him, so to speak, sex is a revolution!
Sexual attraction underlies not only personal,
but also social relations. What they feel for each other
man and woman, are experienced by various subjects of society.
The struggle for power is, in fact, a struggle for a woman.
And the subordination of subjects to the rulers is based ...
-In fear.
- Partly. But in no less degree - on love in the sexiest
sense of the word. Make the masses want you -
and they will change for you the slope of the earth's axis.
Questions, ladies and gentlemen?
I ask you, Herr the revolutionary.
-You talked with us for two hours,
kept in suspense. For us there was no one,
except you. Does it follow from this that all those present in this room
you wanted? LAUGHTER IN THE ROOM
-I would say that you have simplified my theory too much.
But if you put the question this way, then answer it yourself,
only honestly. I answered this question for myself.
I did not want you. I'm a normal man.
But you could not answer my question neither "yes", nor "no".
Would answer "yes" - would be in vain. Would answer "no" - only
would confirm the falsity of your theory.
Nevertheless, I did not leave. I listened to you
with a sinking heart. Do you know why?
Because you ... are right. Paradox.
-Our paradoxes are our life.
-He is either a genius or a maniac, obsessed with sex.
In any case, he can shock. -Shock?
And is it possible to shock a woman posing naked
before a dozen men? -I have to earn,
not to be obligated to Parvus. And there is no
sexual overtones. -In Freud's opinion, sexy
subtext is everywhere. -Herr revolutionary!
You represent a very rare type of sexual aggressor.
You tried to trap me just to shake
my authority in the eyes of the crowd. But, after seeing my hitch,
immediately threw me a lifebuoy. "I beg your pardon, Mr. Freud,
if my is not a very serious matter ...
-You have a critical mind, you do not succumb to advertising, on you
the laws of the crowd do not apply. But your psychotype is usually peculiar,
attacking, already killing, but something prevents you from completing the started
an act of sexual aggression. Yes, yes, maybe, weakness ...
-I extended my hand to the drowning, choked
in their own demagoguery. You call it weakness?
- How quickly your pupils narrow. This reaction I met
only two types of people - serial killers and religious fanatics.
You can become both if you learn to defeat your weaknesses.
- I'm not interested in fighting weakness. I'm interested
to struggle with force. Farewell. -Do you stay in Vienna for long? I would like
learn more about you. Next time, Mr. Freud.
I'm waiting in Brussels.
SPEAKS IN SPANISH
Hello, Jose.
"Leo, have not seen you for a long time, my friend." Glad always!
- I'm not alone today, I'm with Frank. We'll work, we'll work for you
in four hands. - And do not think to argue, amigo!
You're crazy, but I like it.
-Thank you. -Hey, come here.
-Hose wonderful man, he prepares wonderful quesadillas.
From time to time I run from my desk.
Very much helps to get rid of bad thoughts.
Are not you afraid to get your hands dirty?
-Not afraid. -Great. Join now.
Surprised, did not expect to see Trotsky rolling out the dough?
-From what? Hitler is an artist, Mussolini is an enthusiastic motorist.
No. From this they do not cease to be Hitler and Mussolini. Than you are better?
-You know, pictures, cars are all habits of superhumans.
Quesadilla is more primitive, more relevant to the soil,
on which ordinary people walk. -You are confused in the testimony,
Comrade Trotsky. Just as yesterday you talked about yourself as
about the superman who superseded God himself. And now you say the opposite.
"Your blinkers, Frank, make you see the contradictions, even in those cases,
when there are none. Yes, I was a superman in order to decide
tasks that ordinary people can not do. Then I could not allow
to contemplate itself for the cooking. And now I can.
But at any time, if necessary, I will again become a god.
You know, idols at close examination disappoint.
And the more powerful the deity, the stronger the disappointment.
-Convenient logic to substitute faith and not to get stuck on such trifles,
as devotion. "I've always believed the same thing all my life.
For me, the revolution was always a god.
-For me as well. -Nothing like this!
You personified it with your Stalin,
squeezed into the framework of personality. This is normal for ordinary people.
That's why we build myths around our names.
Actually, if you think about it, it's you, not I'm real
apostates. It's you, at the first call of the leader, believe in him, not in the idea.
I never succumbed to this.
I always saw people in the leaders. And, unfortunately, not always
the very best. Alas!
SHEPOT: Trotsky is coming.
- Hello, Vladimir Ilyich.
"You should not have dressed like that, Trotsky. The Plenum of the Congress adopted a decision
about canceling your speech.
I thought ... and I'm ready to do what you asked for.
-Your speech.
Thank you.
Comrade Trotsky has a word.
- Comrades! I, Lev Trotsky, escaped from exile, passed through hell
Tsar's prison, who saw the degradation of the Russian people and the Russian
I consider it my duty to turn to revolutionaries.
True, there are not many of them here. DISSATISFIED COUNTRIES
They settled around Paris, Berlin, London!
You chat, write articles! Fat swim!
You can not save the peasants and send workers, sitting in a coffee house!
You can not, with a cup of coffee, arm the proletariat!
Look at yourself - are not you ashamed?
Yes you are all here ... impotent!
You do not fight! You imitate the struggle, thereby discrediting
the great idea of ​​revolution. Comrade Plekhanov, and it is convenient for you
to talk about the revolution with a full stomach?
Does not it make you jump? A Russian peasant suffers.
Let him wait for another revolution, in highly developed Europe.
Is not that so, Georgi Valentinovich? -Are you finished?
-You, comrade Lenin, what are you smiling at?
Than you are better? Sit in the same coffeehouse at a nearby table
and weave intrigues. You are just as impotent as everyone else.
The Russian revolution tired of tolerating the helplessness of the Paris and Vienna
roosters. She needs new leaders, new fighters.
-Well done! -Mold-of-war Trotsky!
- She, like a woman, is waiting for a real man. Enough talk!
It is time for the Russian revolution. Be a man,
impregnate it, and it will be born of a new, just world.
"Bravo"
-Plox is a revolutionary who can not become a street extremist!
Bad is the revolutionary who is afraid of drowning in the rivers of blood!
Long live the Russian revolution!
Long live the cleansing through the blood!
Thank you! "Comrade Trotsky, it's amazing."
You have surpassed my wildest expectations.
So effectively drop two ballast! -Three. Tell your friends,
from which you take money, that more in their services I do not need.
By the way, you do not need me either.
It's amazing!
"Thank you.
Are we going?
Thank you!
Thank you
-You are an unprincipled bandit. - I'm a revolutionary.
-You were rude to me.
-I taught you to be happy
methods available to me. -That's how you're going to build
your new world? -If you need - yes.
The main thing is that the result should be the same. What does "the same" mean?
-It means that everyone is happy and happy in the end.
-All? -All.
-And are not you taking too much on yourself, comrade revolutionary?
You think you seduced one fragile girl
and now everyone will like it? To all the people?
-And the people are a fragile girl. The masses are their psychology
female. You are by nature passive, waiting for what you offer
man, and then choose the best. So is the people.
Especially - Russian. He is like a student: he never does
the very first step, but it is necessary to appear to a strong confident gentleman,
immediately runs with joy to give himself to him.
-I do not understand how you can respond so disparagingly
about the whole people, for whose happiness you, in my opinion, are struggling.
-No neglect. There is a sober assessment of the object
application of forces. -You would see your face now.
On it contempt for this object in large letters
it is written. -And even if so!
The people who have been despotic for centuries are not worthy of contempt?
-And why fight for the happiness of someone you despise?
-And then that I'm sick of despising. I want to love.
I want everyone around to be worthy of love. Normal persons
I want to see. Beautiful, happy, joyful - that's how you.
That all around were like that. I want to? But I want to.
-What are you doing, buddy ?!
Let's get on with it! We still have a new world to build. Come on!
-General Mamontov broke through the front line at the junction of the 8th and 9th Armies
and went to our rear. -How did you break it? What is the number?
Where is he going? Find out - report back.
"Precisely, comrade prerevvoensoveta. Immediately I'll find out.
BIRTHDAY CHILDREN, SWIST, DRINKED VOICES
-So! Harmon to tudy! Smile!
Do not bother! Smile, guys! -What's happening?
-Get up! Have risen! Have risen!
So here we are - decided to make a photo.
Zhydenko was caught ... a photographer, in the city ...
-Where is it from? -So it's ... we're here oats
expropriated for the needs of the army, and in the yard there is this stolen!
Well, do not waste the same good!
- Comrade Pre-Revolutionary Council!
And you can make a photo with you, eh?
Otherwise they will not believe me. To me, Egorka, orphan of Kazan,
barefoot, that I've been ... under your command served.
And I told them! - photo. A?
"I want everyone around to be worthy of love.
I want to see normal faces.
Beautiful, happy, joyful - that's how you ".
"So you want me to write about this?"
-Well, this is your book, you decide.
What do you think, Jackson, why is there propaganda in the world?
- To convey the position of the state to the masses.
-To draw illusions that you do not want to lose.
The picture of your world is extremely beautiful.
Somewhere on earth there is a paradise, where the good fair titans rule,
which will protect you from any evil. You so want to believe in it,
that your brain rejects any information that contradicts
this picture. Alas, such a self-suggestion moves more likely
banal craving for comfort, but not facts.
-Facts, among other things, and that Lenin is ready to pray
third of the world, and Stalin - his faithful follower.
And it is unlikely that they would have developed this way, whether they really are small people.
-You see, what exact word you have chosen is to pray.
Drop your blinders already, turn your mind on, Frank.
Praying is a religion. That you, as an atheist, must be considered false.
And they did not invent anything new.
Everything was invented before them. Lenin is assigned the role of God the Father,
and Kobe - God the Son. -Yeah. And you - Judah.
-Yes. I heard this expression.
Judas Trotsky ...
"Well, judging by your story, it's true."
You betrayed both Lenin and Parvus in one fell swoop.
And if we say Christian analogies, then the role of Judah is right for you
like no other. "What do you think, Jackson,
would Judas become a negative hero if he betrayed, say,
not Jesus, but the high priests?
-And do you think, if the high priests carried out
a dream of humanity, to whom would they now pray - on them or on Jesus?
-Yes ... For a Stalinist, you have a surprisingly sharp mind.
Till tomorrow, Jackson. By the way, to the note. Neither Lenin nor Parvus
nobody's dreams were realized except his own. Like this.
What do you want from me?
-To me? I have already died a year already. So nothing.
I thought you called me.
-Yesterday another person died because of me,
and I almost did not feel anything. Emptiness inside.
-No ... You did not become either a serial killer or a religious fanatic.
You have become something more terrible.
-You are ... unoriginal.
Since I was kicked out of the Union, I hear it quite often.
-Manyak kills others to feel.
A fanatic kills himself and others to feel.
But you have not felt anything for a long time, Herr the revolutionary.
No love, no pity, no hatred, no compassion for the victims.
-What do you want to hear? Excuses?
- When I looked you in the eye and saw how quickly narrowed
your pupils at the time of stress. This was beautiful.
And now ... you know what I see?
Nothing. Emptiness in the eyes.
You are indifferent even to the death of others ...
... and his.
-The sense of death is the lot of the weak, Mr. Freud.
I remember you reproached me for my weakness. So, I became strong.
I'm not afraid to die.
-Your indifference to death is quite natural.
Do you know who is absolutely not afraid to die?
-Who? -The one who is already ...
... dead.