SUBTITLES: N.PETRULYEVICH, I.KIRIK, O. KULAGIN, E.MASLENNIKOVA,
E.DOBROVITSKAYA, A. PRYAKH
CHRONICLE CHRONICLE SPEAKS IN ENGLISH
"Oh, Frank, my English is terrible." I have to unwind all the time
film at the beginning to catch the nuances of the commentary.
Do you believe in American journalism?
-No. But I need to know under what sauce Westerners cheat
philistine.
-Can you just be jealous? Imagine yourself there, in the square,
at the head of the parade. - Do not feel sorry for me.
I did not lose. -Triumfatorom you just do not look.
In captivity of this house, under supervision. Where are your victories, Trotsky?
Here it is:
... my victories.
And you, do you think Stalin is the winner?
-Meally. He created an empire.
-Nothing like this. He's a victim. Hostage of own fears.
He lives in a world full of enemies. Often, however, fictional.
-You can think, you do not have enemies. -Anyway, I feel
much freer.
-What's wrong with you? -Heck.
- Lev Davidovich.
Lev Davidovich.
-Eh! Turn off this your ...
-You accuse Stalin of everything, but meanwhile it's you, and he did not return
the death penalty. Yes, it was necessary.
Who "you"?
-Revolution.
-Yes, I'll take this one. It is somehow more habitual. Although we fit
Do not choose weapons, but the pillars on which we are hung up.
We were intoxicated by success. But to take the capital is not the same as taking the whole country.
"Even if this is so, we must hold power at all costs."
Since it is in our hands.
-The same thing Stalin offers to Lenin. They are considering
your replacement on Shchastny.
-Where did you get this information? -It does not matter. Your authority in the fleet
weak, and a combination with Shchastny could strengthen power.
Naturally, leaving you behind the brackets.
-Yakov Mikhailovich. -Yes?
-And why are you so frank with me?
-I will say so ...
I am also concerned about the strengthening of Stalin. So I help his opponent.
-We are not opponents.
Yes, I...
Then you have nothing to worry about.
-Why are we waiting for him here? Was he unable to receive us in the office?
- There is no cabinet in Shchastny. He is always on ships or inspects
garrison. -No, just wants to show us,
that we are on its territory. - Here he comes.
- Comrade Pre-Military Council, once again I ask to forgive. State of the fleet
requires my constant presence here.
- I understand everything, Alexey Mikhailovich. The first hero of Russia is not necessary
make excuses. Newspapers call your ice hike heroic.
"And your irony is inappropriate, Comrade Trotsky." Only thanks to a friend
The private Baltic Fleet is here now, not the Germans.
-Can we talk in private?
As you know, I arrived on matters of extreme importance. The Germans are coming
to Petrograd. We do not have any possibility to retain them. Breaking the line
front, they will occupy Kronstadt. In order to avoid the seizure of the Baltic
We decided to prepare the fleet for destruction. I understand the measure
extraordinary, but there is no other way out. -Kronstadt they can not take. We will
to defend himself to the last sailor. -Of course of course. But you know,
according to the Treaty of Brest we have no right ...
-My people risked their lives, removing the fleet first from Revel
in Helsingfors, and then here, in Kronstadt. And now you want,
so I ordered them to blow it up? -Exactly, exactly ...
The operation is secret, so please prepare
a few reliable people. Of course, their work will
well paid ... -I will not participate in this!
- It's not about your desires, Shchastny. That's an order.
-I refuse to obey him.
-I want to remind you of the oath. -I did not swear an oath to you, but to the country.
And the fleet was not saved so that you would destroy it.
-Agentura Dzerzhinsky reports on the conspiracy to liberate the Romanovs.
-This is to be expected. Holding the king in the Urals, we create
for them a flag, a figure around which you can unite.
The situation with the king must be solved in one way or another.
It can not be kept suspended. What are the opinions?
-We will build an open process. With maximum lighting in the press.
Let us unfold before the world a picture of the entire reign of Romanov:
two wars, pogroms, famine ... -And the Red Army is ready to carry out
safety of his movement? The railway is controlled by Czechs,
rebels after your attempt to disarm them.
"Even if Comrade Trotsky organizes the transportation of the tsar,
what I do not doubt, what will be the possible results?
Those who support us know perfectly well about the crimes of the tsar,
but those who are against us - those of us can not be persuaded.
-SERMUX, immediately call to Moscow Shchastnogo.
Why? .. For the reward. He's a hero, after all.
Skip
You can not go on. -And why else?
-Wait here.
Will you allow me? -Yes.
Hello, comrade Shchastny. Sit down.
Sit down, take a seat.
-That means ... it's not a reward?
- You ignored my order.
Did you really think that I would leave it just like this?
-Your orders are incompetent. It means that they are harmful.
Are they harmful? For whom? -For Russia.
-You are a military man and you should know that failure to comply with the order in the army -
this is treason. Arrest him.
Raskolnikov, did you hear what I said?
-Aleksiy Mikhailovich ... give up your weapons.
-You will not give anything. The court will justify me.
- Well, you have nothing to fear.
-And I'm not afraid. Do not forget, Trotsky, on whose bayonets holds
your power. - Take him.
-Saving Shchastny, you defied the fleet. Radical elements
among the sailors want to overthrow the Bolshevik government
and establish the dictatorship of the Baltic Fleet, led by Shchastny.
- So arrest them. - You have already arrested the Czechs -
it worked perfectly! -Arests only exacerbate irritation
in the Navy. -We are power. We should not
to adjust. - Lev Davidovich, I think that I express
general opinion, saying that for our dusty work
you are very impressive today. -And we neglect in vain
aesthetics of the revolution. Wearing cuffs, we remain strangers to the masses.
-At finally they started talking about the main thing! "Now, Comrade Koba,
the danger of a coup, and Shchastny sought this.
- Do you have any proof? -I have confidence.
This is more important, Comrade Sverdlov. Shchastny is a danger
for a revolution that is easier to prevent than to combat it
consequences. -And how do you fight?
Every hour that Shchastny spends in prison,
works for him and against us. -As with the family of the Romanovs,
which we only tease the enemy. I believe that it is necessary ...
return the death penalty. I'm against the return of execution!
-Lev Davidovich, the abolition of the death penalty is the greatest achievement
revolution. -Yes. Who will have to sacrifice,
to save this revolution.
We are surrounded by enemies. Against us all: the Germans, the Czechs, the Entente, the Kappel,
internal enemy. There is a war in which we will not win
without such an instrument. -We will push people away.
-On the contrary. I think they will approve of us. We will show the people that we are ready to stand
for his interests until the end.
-Yes, I think, a revolution can not do without such an instrument.
The question is, which class will he be directed against.
Sit down. Sit down, sit down. The very idea that the possibility of the death penalty
there are, many sober.
I am for".
-But it was not.
-You can not let him get out of this. He is the enemy.
It's a question of survival ...
ours and the revolution. -It will be justified.
One of my testimonies is not enough. -I will support you.
Do what I ask. The rest I will settle. Good?
And you know what? Do not be afraid of it.
From conversations with the officers of the fleet, I learned that Comrade Shchastny spread
panic rumors about my alleged intentions to destroy the fleet.
Disclosing this information, Comrade Shchastny pursued
the only goal is the creation of a counter-revolutionary
conspiracy in the navy. -If this is a conspiracy, then where else?
conspirators? - Comrade Shchastny ...
"In time, Comrade Shchastny, we'll bring everyone to the surface."
That's all I wanted to say. -Well, the defense has no more questions
to the witness. -That means, the court ...
-The charge is still a witness - the Commissioner of the Naval General Staff
Comrade Raskolnikov wants to give evidence.
- Comrade judge, Raskolnikov is not declared as a witness,
it is not in the materials of the investigation.
-What is more important for us - the truth or procedure?
It's too serious.
If a witness wants to testify, he must be heard.
-We are ready to listen to him.
-Captain of the first rank Shchastny led among the leadership of the People's Commissariat
counter-revolutionary agitation. He also invited me to join
to conspiracy to overthrow the Soviet power and establish
dictatorship of the Baltic Fleet, in fact his personal dictatorship.
- He's lying! Do not believe him! Bastard! -Well, stop now!
-Selling creature! - Bring him out of the hall.
-Sit. -Busk! The creature is corrupt!
He's lying! Do not believe him! He's lying!
"Comrade Raskolnikov, perhaps you will remind us all,
when did this all happen? -What exactly?
-When Captain Shchastny invited you to participate
in a conspiracy? I can not tell you the exact day.
-How do you ... Well, at least, maybe, you will call us a month?
-It was April, it seems to me. -How is it? And why are you only
now remember this? Why did not you tell your leadership then?
Why did not they tell the investigation? -I fully and fully realize
his own fault for this. - Tell me, where was the meeting scheduled?
-I do not remember. In my opinion, it was in my office.
- Comrade Shchastny, maybe he called you some names of people who
a little earlier joined the conspiracy? -No.
-No? So, there were only you and he at the meeting?
-Yes. -Clear. Well, to a friend
Raskolnikov, I have no more questions. And call him a witness ...
Well, sorry, the language does not turn. The prosecution never provided
no convincing proof of so-called treason
my client. On the contrary, everything you heard from the defense,
characterizes the captain as a patriot and faithful servant of the Russian people.
I will end on this.
-The court leaves for the meeting.
"Comrade Trotsky, where are you going?" Comrade Trotsky!
You have no right. -Sit to your place!
Sit down. On his own. A place.
"Comrade Trotsky, you can not be here."
-For exceptional state importance
In this process, I must be sure that you will issue the correct verdict.
-You do not have the right to dictate to us what to do. There are rules!
- To hell with your rule if they contradict common sense.
You must all understand: there is an enemy sitting in the courtroom.
- He's a hero!
-Yes, but, making a heroic feat, he created his popularity,
intending to use it against Soviet power.
This counter-revolutionary game has failed, and the punishment must be
as severe as possible.
I will regard any attempt to mitigate the sentence of Shchastny
as treason. I beg.
-The shooting will give the sailors a martyr. -No.
He will give them God in my face. Believe me, I know the psychology of the masses.
-They will raise a rebellion. - They will not be raised - they do not have a leader.
They are unorganized. The main thing is to get ahead of them, to act first.
-How? Maybe slap him right here?
-In the center of Moscow? They'll hear.
- They will not hear.
Agranov!
- Stand here.
Creek!
THE MOTOR SPEAKED
You can not see anything! Headlight on it!
-Do not work.
Aim in the light.
-Wait!
Aim!
Pli!
-Trogsky!
You executed a man whose little finger was not worth it.
Killing you, I save Russia.
-Dad...
Dad, I forgot the pencils!
-This. Hush. -Daddy, it hurts!
-It does not hurt.
Quiet. Quiet.
All is well.
You're doing fine. Well done. Come on.
- By abolishing the ban on the death penalty for your own personal purposes, you have opened
thus the Pandora's box. You could not not understand this. The next victim
for this immediately became the Romanovs. -The tsar's family needed it
not just to intimidate or deprive the enemy of hope. No!
First of all - to shake up your own ranks, show them:
retreat is impossible, there is a complete victory ahead or complete ruin.
-And you know that the son of Nicholas II, a small czarevitch,
did not die right away? He was finished off with a bayonet.
-Not interested in ever. I confess I do not understand this interest.
I consider him shameful, philistine. THE MOTOR SPEAKED
From the point of view of morality, history, the death of the Tsarevich is not more significant,
than the fate of hundreds of thousands of children doomed by tsarism to perish.
If you are so pitiful, remember them. Or their lives are less significant
in the eyes of the creator? We did not follow the bourgeois
principle of guilt. No! We were led by a historical necessity.
Yes that's it! NOISE FOR THE WINDOW
Do you have to do this now, when I work?
-Okay, if you are talking about morality, what will you say about words
Voroshilov, who called you (quote) "author and inspirer of the red
terror. Trotsky strengthened his personal power by mass executions
deserved communists "?
-Voroshilov ... I, too, remembered the master of doom.
-He quotes here lists of people whose death sentences
is your signature. -Jackson, you can not change the world,
nothing in it without changing. In terms of class struggle, my actions
fully justified. I executed the enemies who wanted to return
people into slavery. And do not think that they did not shoot us.
"Comrade prerevolutionary council ..." "Continue, Comrade Commander."
So, the enemy will try to regain this part of the front.
Therefore, our main task is to strengthen the bridgehead as much as possible.
-No! It is necessary to develop the offensive.
Throw all the forces into a breakthrough while the enemy is in a panic. Of course,
loss of human material is inevitable, but in this section
front ...
Comrade Tukhachevsky, where are you going?
- To your car. You want to take my place, Comrade Trotsky.
So I'll take yours.
"Comrades, can I have some tea?"
Tell me, why are you with us?
-I serve Russia. -It's clear. But all the same?
-Below back I was captain, now I command the army.
-That's a question of ambition. Our views you do not share.
-And what is more important to you? My loyalty or the coincidence of views?
We are both supporters of a strong army, we definitely share this view.
You did the impossible - created the spirit of this army.
Sacrificial, exalted. The soldiers accepted you, they believed in you.
A month ago you were called only a visiting Jew,
now the Red Army soldiers say: "The Jews are in the Kremlin, Trotsky - no, this is ours."
-Your words flatter me, but the people's love is an unreliable currency.
In the royal army, too, were favorites. -Among them there was no Napoleon.
"What are you standing there, Sermuk, like a statue?" Report.
- Lev Davidovich, an attempt was made on Lenin.
Eserka Fanny Kaplan shot a revolver.
-We return to Moscow, immediately.
-The terrible is behind. Doctors are sure:
Vladimir Ilyich will get out.
But such a serious injury will not pass without a trace.
- Including for us. I think we should learn from this story.
-What kind?
-Vladimir Ilich is a supporter of tough measures. And, perhaps, we should
Use his absence to mitigate the policy.
"What exactly do you propose, Comrade Kamenev?"
- Stop the bloodshed, proclaim the policy of national
reconciliation, try to start a dialogue. -With whom? With the bourgeoisie? With the priests?
We create a future, in which we take not all.
Let them die 30, 50, 70%, the rest will go with us.
In communism. -Yes, how can you not see?
The enemy responds to our violence with the same violence.
-Not that. We will respond more harshly. We will reach the limits on which
he does not have the courage. Cruelty will be ... biblical.
We will cancel the court, the law.
We will shoot several significant groups hostile to us
interlayers, we organize concentration camps, we will debug the machine of suppression
counter-revolution and will punish. Not only the perpetrators, but also those,
who is potentially dangerous. The enemy must clearly know: for every drop of our
blood we will shed their river. This is the birth of a new world,
and childbirth without blood, dirt, shit does not happen.
The question is about survival: we or they. Only by proving to the enemy,
that we will not stop where he stops, we can
break his will.
-I agree with Comrade Trotsky.
-I will acquaint you with your position of Lenin. -No. No time to wait.
Act immediately. Where is Kaplan?
- In the cell, of course.
-Call it now, so that the information is in tomorrow's
newspapers. -Er still interrogated,
she has not yet named all the names.
-We do not need them. We will not execute concrete guilty persons, but those,
whom we do not take with us to the future. This is the highest form of class struggle.
Soon, very soon the Soviet Union that I created will take half of the world.
And then all.
So how do you think I won or lost?
-All depends on whether you like the world you created.
Did you get what you wanted? Or something else happened?
- It's a living process, Frank. Yes, life always introduces inevitable adjustments.
At least, I did everything to defeat the enemies ... of the revolution.
- Which became all those who did not support the Bolsheviks.
-Yes. Because the Bolsheviks were a revolution. Only they defended
the interests of the working class: peasants, soldiers, sailors. Only they.
-And then with whom did you fight in Kronstadt? There was no
noblemen and priests. The same sailors and workers who brought you
to power.
-3.5 years Bolshevik usurpers
hold power. 3,5 years prowl
through the villages their outfits, peeling the peasants and dooming them to hunger
death. For 3.5 years the Bolsheviks sacrifice their bloody gods:
Lenin and Trotsky!
-You have created such a convincing myth about revolutionary sailors,
that they themselves believed it. -You sure that they will not be supported
workers of Peter? - Who owns the newspaper -
owns minds, Comrade Tukhachevsky. You printed that the insurgency had raised
Tsarist General Kozlovsky, and the workers hate this audience pohlesche us.
-Working hate you? -Well, some part.
Workers are heterogeneous, but this is the lesser of our problems.
-We demand real democracy! SUPPORTING CROWNS OF THE CROWD
We demand to give the road to non-Party people! CROWD: Yes!
-Return to the Soviets, crushed by the Iron Paw of the Communists,
their real power! CROWD: Yes!
-To enable the peasant to work on the cultivated plot of land
be the master! CROWD: Yes!
- Tell me how you are going to suppress the mutiny.
- I would prefer to give up this mission. If I may.
-Why? - It's not the front.
It's one thing to fight with the enemy's army, quite another to punish one's own.
Workers, sailors. -Since when
they have become for you their own, Comrade Tukhachevsky?
In any case, there is not much valor in it.
- And let's look at it from the other side. It's a challenge, it's a test.
your qualities as a commander. Good afternoon. Consider it
as a tour. -Gastrol?
-Gastrol. You play the violin. Here you have just the first violin.
You are a talented professional and always perform the tasks set for you
tasks, so, I think, it will not be very difficult for you.
"From here, from this place, we, the revolutionary sailors
Kronstadt, we will begin what we should have done long ago.
Liberation of Russia! They abandoned Nicholas, comrades,
we will throw out also communists! Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
- Stop it. Stop it!
What's that smell? -Solar. The corpses are burning.
"Comrade Trotsky!"
Do you remember me? Agranov Yakov. We shchastnogo slapped in the courtyard,
Remember!
I'm in the Cheka now.
Work we have no end!
They have friends after all, friends, relatives - it's understandable,
what public. We must deal with all this ruffian!
-Lenin is completely bad. Nadia says, it is weakening fast, the consciousness loses
at work. He was put in a couch in the study - he lies almost all the time.
-And who manages? -Stalin.
While you were gone, he became stronger. I gathered around me new people,
promoted them to leadership positions. It became the eastern vizier.
- Hello, Comrade Trotsky. -Hello.
-To Ilyich is not allowed now, doctors are allowed to work only in the morning.
-I do not for a long time. -We all adjust,
Comrade Trotsky. I'm afraid, and you will ...
- I'll be back tomorrow. - Tomorrow Ilyich in Gorki.
Come to me at eight o'clock, we will discuss all the issues.
I would have talked with you now, but, unfortunately, the affairs are notorious - the turnover.
The war is over, you have done your work.
Now it's our turn.
ALARM MUSIC
-I had as a child ... in the courtyard ...
still in Simbirsk ...
lived a janitor.
So, he assumed that almost all the evil in the world from books.
They were for him something like instructions from the other world.
He seriously believed that books could be blinded. I laughed at him
then, and now I think: "Maybe he's right and we are blinded?"
"I have always been aware of my own affairs, and I do not regret anything.
"Yes.
And I'm very sorry that I did this to the king.
He did not understand anything.
Did not have time to realize.
I did not feel the inevitability of death.
He did not have to lie to the children, tell them that everything would be fine,
as you had. You promised the children that everything will be fine.
Yes . . .
The enemy must be kept waiting for death.
Enjoying the fear that will devour him from the inside,
as Stalin does. -I do not give a damn about him.
This is not a prison, and I'm free. "Do not lie to yourself, Leo!"
You run into a world of fantasy and ghosts, because in you
Fear settled. Whatever you say to yourself, you know perfectly well,
that you are alive only because the mustachioed allows you to live.
- That's enough. -Every minute you look
in the faces of people around you and ask yourself: "Who will betray
you, who of them and when? "- Shut up!
-All your nature screams from the inside: "Hurry! Quick!" - because
no more urine to endure! -I'm not afraid of death.
-You are afraid ... All are afraid, and you are afraid. You are the same person as everyone else.
Not God, not a prophet - a man of flesh and blood. And you are afraid, because
you do not know what's there on the other side.
And what if I have to answer?
What will you answer them?
And you say, you are not afraid.
GO
Go, go out into the street. Finish it all right now.
-Well, let's. I'm not afraid of you. Do you hear? Where are you there?
ON-SPANISH: Senor, are you all right? Senor, what's the matter with you?
Senor ...
Pablo, rather call an ambulance, the señora is bad.
- Leo!
Sylvia, call the doctor.