SUBTITLES: O. KULAGIN, E. MASLENNIKOVA, E. DOBROVITSKAYA, A. PRYAKH
-Ah, hell, it's you.
-He is very unhappy with you.
And if he is dissatisfied with someone ... -I need more time.
Today
Do you understand me well? Today.
Yes.
-Frank ... -Come on, please.
-Hello! Sorry, but today there will not be an interview.
-What happened? - Lion had an attack. A heart.
Now he's in order more or less. But it will take a rest.
-Well, well, I hope everything will work out.
-Frank!
I've been waiting for you for the past hour. Rise quickly.
Well, why are you stuck there? Time is short.
Natasha, I feel great.
Jackson, do you sleep at least sometimes?
-Bad. -Why so?
- Nightmare. How are you?
-Much better than doctors think. How much did your doctor give me?
Year? Half a year? Less?
Never listen to what the doctors say. They only ...
HEAVY SPEAKS: ... confusing. -Can you rest now today?
Shall we go to the lake? "Natashenka, do not worry.
As we already finish. Yes, Frank?
-Yes. -So that's great.
We will not waste time.
Well, begin.
-Your most vivid memory of childhood?
-Oh you!
Let me see...
I was four years old. Walked in the garden with a nanny - cook's daughter.
She saw a bite in the bushes and ... poked him with a stick.
And it turned out to be a viper. Nurse ran away - I could not.
I literally pinned down. Paralyzing horror.
I could not do anything. Legs grew to the ground.
Fortunately, the snake did not touch me. Has crept away.
-And the moment when it became clear - everything, victory? Do you remember him?
"Of course.
Clearly I remember. I received a telegram from Tukhachevsky.
At that time he suppressed the rebellion of Antonov, our last
a serious enemy. I remember word for word:
"The insurgency is eliminated
Soviet power is established elsewhere throughout the world. "
This is a historical moment. Remember it.
I want to appeal to the people. Wire to the nearest station.
Let them gather all: the population, the soldier - of all who can.
THE REVOLUTIONARY SONG
- Picked up all who could.
SIGNALIT
-Put on livelihood. -I have nothing.
-I did not eat for three days. I'm dying. Give me something.
-I'm sorry, but I really have nothing.
- Forgive me, for God's sake! -Nothing.
Thank you.
-Standing physics in your spare time? -I do not study. I'm interested.
I want to get to the point, to find out how everything is arranged.
-This strikingly distinguishes you from the current political elite.
But they, on the contrary, believe that everyone already knows for a long time,
and the reality is likely to fall under its theory. -Are you talking about someone specifically?
Do you know who Gorky is talking to now?
-Lev Davidovich, in Russia
30 million people are starving.
And most of all, the poor are suffering. These are the ones for which we are with you
and we are making this great social transformation.
-The government is doing everything possible. -I mean citizens.
My friend Professor Prokopovich, the most prominent economist,
proposes to organize collection of donations to the hungry.
-I do not think you will be able to raise enough money.
From whom will you ask? There is no money in the country.
-He seems to be seriously believing himself to be God, hoping to change
social and economic laws. -And why do you think he has
nothing happens? So far, he has achieved everything he wanted.
-If you really want to find out how everything is arranged, go to the higher
technological. - I'm already learning there.
-Yes? Yes, on faculty.
-And I'm teaching there. On the economic side. Prokopovich Sergey Nikolaevich.
-Sedov. The Lion of Sedov. -Very nice.
-My and Prokopovich know in the West.
And, you see, the collected funds there can be significant.
We will purchase products in Europe and America and deliver them in the most
suffering areas. But without government support, this is impossible.
-I understood you. Anything else? - The other day I met with Blok.
He is very sick. Physicians who can help him, in the city
just did not remain. It needs to be taken to Finland, but in the GPU
do not give documents, allegedly on the personal orders of Dzerzhinsky.
-In the near future I will raise this issue.
-Thank you. Thank you, Lev Davidovich. I had no doubt.
-I suggest Professor Prokopovich correct.
In America there is overproduction. They burn excess grain in the furnaces
and with extra milk they feed the pigs. They will gladly sell us
surpluses at the lowest price. -You thought about political
consequences? This will put us in a disadvantageous position before the West.
- Spit if it helps to solve the problem of hunger. Anyway
we will have to establish contacts with them. "Comrade Lenin, do you think,
can we accept handouts from the exploiting classes of the West?
-That the rich share with the poor-that's right. But, if it will be
charity, it will be humiliating. Comrade Stalin is right.
We have to pay. Otherwise, in the eyes of the peasants we will look
inconsistent. -Restaurants are of little interest
our sequence with you. They are starving to death.
-That means we can and should take advantage of their mood.
Right now, when people eat people on the Volga, we can with the most rabid
energy to seize church values ​​and sell them to the West.
-We will encounter resistance. -I really hope so.
And the more priests we will be able to shoot, the better.
I'm talking about the resistance of the peasants. -You do not need to overestimate
their importance. The village is now weak, but we are strong. It is necessary to use
situation. Comrades, if there are no more questions for today ...
-Vladimir Ilyich, I ... sent you a note about Blok and Gumilyov.
Did you get acquainted? -The unit moved to positions
counterrevolution. It is dangerous to release it abroad. We do not know what from him
wait and what views he will preach.
-And what are you afraid of, Felix Edmundovich? Epigrams?
Unfounded repression against poets, we only demonstrate
own weakness. -Foundable?
Do you question the work of the GPU? -I...
- That's enough! Comrades ... I'm sorry, I feel unwell.
Let's continue next time.
Thank you.
Lev Davidovich, stay for a moment, I beg of you.
I do not know how long I have left ... -Vladimir Ilyich ...
"Take care of me of your vulgar pity, Trotsky."
We were never friends. But lately we've learned
tell each other the truth. It's ... it's beyond any friendship, in my opinion.
Let's be frank. I must be sure that the work of my life
after my death will fall into safe hands. Stalin is rude and not far off.
And he marks leaders. And you turned your manners away from yourself
all in the party. Tell me frankly, you are able to moderate
your fervor and stop setting yourself against Dzerzhinsky?
He is a real force. We need it.
-If I agree, how do you see my future actions?
I. Stalin: Comrade Dzerzhinsky, come on.
Any economic theory should be based on a specific
historical research ...
-Professor Prokopovich?
Come with us. - I have a lecture. Allow me to finish?
Nothing.
Hey, what are you doing ?!
Leave him! - Quiet, I said!
And I'll get to you.
TROTSKY HANDS
-Father ... I never asked for anything. And took the name of his mother,
so that no one knows that I am your son, to achieve everything myself.
-If your professor is innocent, he will be released.
-I beg, help. -We have already discussed this with you.
- Can you imagine that Professor Prokopovich is an enemy?
-I believe in the competence of the GPU staff and I'm not going to tell you anything.
to explain, the more justify.
-The left is right.
-What? -We were arrested in the museum department
archivist. He is 70 years old. Throughout Moscow, the intelligentsia is poisoned,
grab writers, philosophers, teachers. They are not terrorists.
-That's it!
LETTER: "Hello Lev Davidovich: In case you are too busy,
to follow the news, I will inform you: Block died three weeks ago,
Gumilyov was shot the day before yesterday. I do not blame you for their death,
guilt lies with us all. To defeat the enemy, we created Moloch,
they nurtured him, nurtured the blood of the victims. Now the enemies are defeated,
but he wants more. Guilty, innocent, enemies, friends -
does not matter. He is hungry, he needs food. He started with poets, because
they are weaker than others, but, having grown teeth, he will take prey more seriously.
You have cast down the persecutor, so do not become it yourself.
Be merciful. Maksim Gorky".
-You were the second person in the country. Could not you stop it?
-The civil war is over, but the world revolution was still
ahead. And the main battle - for the minds - we still had to win.
War, revolution ... You always justify violence by emergency
circumstances. But in reality you have doomed to death thousands of innocent people.
How do you justify this? -In the name of the common victory ...
sometimes it is necessary to concede. Yes, I sacrificed them.
But later he saved many others.
When? - At the plenum.
We will oppose him together and withdraw from the Central Committee.
-But Stalin just will not give up.
-Yes, of course, he will try to stir up a mutiny. But with what forces?
The people do not know him. Everything he can count on, -
this is Dzerzhinsky, not the Cheka. "In that case, I'll raise the army."
- And destroy everything we fought for?
The second civil war will incinerate the country.
What do you want to rule, a desert?
-Dzherzhinsky was carried away. The need for terror has disappeared,
and prisons burst from prisoners. Well, I would still plant a counter,
so no, he took up the professor. -First poets, now professors!
Leo, you calm down. We decide the fate of the country and the revolution, and you are being treated
about some kind of intelligentsia! -Are you okay?
- Do not feel sorry for me!
And no one should be pitied. You must be strong and ruthless -
only then you can win. Nadia, I'm fine,
I'm fine. -I can see in what order you are.
You need to rest, but not work. And you are indulging him, Lev Davidovich.
- I called him. -I'll take it.
True, Lev Davidovich, go away.
-Trotsky, did you understand me? -Yes. Yes.
Have a rest.
The phone rings.
-Secretariat. Fotieva. -Lidia Alexandrovna, Stalin.
-Ah, hello, Iosif Vissarionovich.
-Good afternoon. Give me Ilyich. -And he's not, he's on a walk.
-One? -To my mind,
with Lev Davidovich. Something to tell him when he'll be back?
-It's not worth it. Thank you, Lydia Alexandrovna.
-And this is an act, comrade Ilyin!
Sit down. You have to run after your colleagues,
and you, therefore, have appeared. They showed consciousness.
-I do not find it possible to hide, if they are looking for me. Let me find out,
What are they accusing me of? -Is this important?
-And still? -In refusal to cooperate
with Soviet power, if you want. -I did not refuse to cooperate.
with your power.
- "Your"? Is not she yours, Ivan Alexandrovich?
Have not we brought you freedom from age-old oppression?
-You really brought freedom to people ... of a different kind -
freedom from conscience.
- Do you know how this house is called among the people?
-The ship of death.
-Well, I'm asking aboard.
-In response to the restriction of freedom of speech, suppression of the system
independent higher education in the country, in response to arrests,
The prosecution of the teaching staff of universities we declare
general indefinite strike.
And we offer students, teachers, everyone,
who cares about the fate of education in Russia, join us.
-Done new tyrants! Down with the new kings!
ALARM MUSIC
Down with the new tyrants! CROWD: Down with the new tyrants!
-Done new kings! CROWD: Down with the new kings!
-Done new tyrants! CROWD: Down with the new tyrants!
-Done new kings!
- Thank you, Commissioner. -It's not worth it, Comrade Trotsky.
I understand everything: the mistakes of youth ... Who does not happen?
I did not make out. -Thanks again.
{}
Come along.
-What the hell are you doing ?! -That you should have done, -
uphold freedom and justice! -What do you understand about justice,
Snotty ?! -A lion!
- Do not interfere. Let me talk with my son.
Do you even understand that my enemies will take advantage of this?
You hit me in the back, you're ruining what I'm building.
-What are you building? Bright future? With whom you will go there,
if you destroy everyone who thinks differently? With wordless slaves
without brains? I do not want such a future. You are not a revolutionary
and not a prophet, you are a hypocrite, an executioner and a usurper! You're the worst of all!
I loved you, you were everything to me.
But now I see how small you are, how scared you are for your little world.
I hate you. And I do not want to see.
Leo ... - Leave him alone!
Let him go.
Which of them is the most authoritative? -Ilyin, I suppose.
-Why arrested? -Don't worry, we're just here
do not call. -I asked the question.
-Effect of counter-revolution. -In any form?
-Explain. -Take, I want to talk.
- It's time to waste.
yes, sir!
Do you know who I am? -Yes.
-Oh well. I will not go around in circles. We intend to put an end to the internal
counter-revolution, which you and the like support you.
But I would like to give you a chance to escape punishment. And in return for me
You will need proof of your loyalty.
A collective letter signed by you, your colleagues, with a public
recognition of Soviet power. I will not hide - we need you, your mind,
Your knowledge to rebuild the country anew and make it the greatest
in the world. In return, you get decent living conditions for you and your families.
It's impossible for me. -Why?
-You are a liar, a thief and a murderer.
Under the guise of freedom you brought to people the greatest slavery. You killed the Russians
more than in any of the wars known in the history of Russia.
And after that you ask me why?
-You know what? Do not wring your hands. You lose, learn to look
to the future. -Future?
Your future has already come. Here, in these stone chambers.
Here it is, look. All your achievements will be based on pain,
torture, fear. You are tearing people's admission of loyalty to you and your
ideas of torture. -Your escapades
I absolutely do not touch, although, it seems, you are sincere in your gusts.
If we are such a creature of hell, why did the people support us?
The power was supported by the mob, not the people. Your revolution is a rebellion of a bandit,
the criminal. The rest were intimidated or tempted by the idea of ​​an earthly material
paradise. This is the cunning of Satan. -We just restored
justice. For you, the earthly paradise is the Russian Empire of pattern
commercials of 1913. Well, tell this to the starving peasants,
tell the workers you held in check from drunkenness, ignorance.
Hebrews tell me who did not have the right to settle in your neighborhood.
-The world you destroyed, Trotsky, was imperfect.
There were scoundrels in him.
You made all the bastards. You or the executioner, or applauding his slave.
Your revolution is vulgar. Militant vulgarity.
You keep on fear. It's not for long. If the people do not overthrow
you, you will strangle each other yourself.
-Okay. Will you sign the letter? -No.
-Good. Well, if you are ready to go to death - your will.
Yes, you doom your comrades too.
-No. They doom you to death.
-The strike of professors is the same Kronstadt rebellion,
Only with textbooks instead of weapons and not on the battlefield, but in the classrooms.
Therefore, it is necessary to do the same: suppress mutiny and not be considered
with no sacrifices. -We have detained the most
dangerous participants in the conspiracy of professors. 63 people.
Their shooting will sober up the rest of the professors and active students.
Those who continue will repeat their fate.
-How long?
-Sorry? -Doubts.
This property of the developed mind. Only a fool and a scoundrel do not doubt.
If we repeatedly destroy dissenters with us,
with whom do we end up as a result? -I think Lev Davidovich
no worse than you and I know that these professors are ideological enemies.
We can not endure endlessly their counter-revolutionary antics.
-Yes, but there's nothing to shoot them for. -They participated in the counter-revolutionary
conspiracy. -The invented.
Fictional by you. Their whole conspiracy is the refusal to work in conditions,
which we impose on them. The shooting of the world's most popular intellectuals
we will alienate the intellectuals of the West, many of whom
support. Therefore, we will remain without credits,
technologies, specialists, without which our industrialization will suffocate.
-Will we dance to the tune of the West? -Yes, we will, if it helps us
overtake them. While we are weaker, we must hide our pride and learn everything,
what can teach us.
-Ilyin, on the way out.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Apparently, my turn came. Farewell.
Farewell!
- Let's go faster!
-In war, violence was justified.
Fear of repression is the weapon of the weak on the road to victory.
But to pardon is the right of the strong.
This is the privilege of the winners. Miluya, we prove to the whole world:
we have won, we are confident in ourselves and we can not be afraid of the dissenters.
-Everything is clear ... -Tourist Lenin ...
minute
What exactly do you propose? Endure endlessly counter-revolutionary attacks?
-No. Send them out of the country as an undesirable element.
- Yes, this is a gift for them. Abroad, they will continue
counter-revolutionary activity. -Yes, let him. What, there it is not?
There are plenty of enemies. Professors will only merge into a common
howling. But we can get much more from this action.
-Do you lose? - Let's finish him.
And what do you think we get? -Of people. The very ones who are now
they do not believe us. And we will show them that we are not afraid of a different opinion.
You can bark, but not here. Get out, we are without you yourself
somehow. - Either it's stupid,
or counter-revolution. -Felix Edmundovich,
I think, and so the position is clear. Let's move on to the vote.
Only members of the Politburo vote, therefore, Felix Edmundovich, I ask you
abstain. So, who is for supporting the proposal
Comrade Stalin?
-Confirm. - I already said, I did not mean anything.
sign ... -Change!
-Who to support Comrade Trotsky's proposal?
-Confirm that you will never return to Russia
under pain of death. If they let you out.
-The accused, in case of consent to leave at his own expense, is released
with the obligation to leave the RSFSR within five days.
Otherwise, it will be kept in a special department before expulsion.
stage order. Is everyone clear?
-Two votes to three passes the offer of a friend
Trotsky. Felix Edmundovich, I ask you to prepare for the expulsion
from the country of all the most dangerous, in your opinion, representatives
intellectuals. Cleanse Russia.
-Lev ...
- Mom told me everything. Dad, I wanted to ...
- Karsavin!
Luzsky!
Trubetskoy!
Prokopovich!
Franc!
Berdyaev!
Busheslavsky!
Kizevetter!
"It's not what you wanted, I know, but they still have life."
Perhaps they will be able to return when I correct everything here.
-Ilyin!
Goblets!
Novikov!
Yasensky!
Ugryumov!
Flowers!
Metitsky!
Romodanovsky!
Siberian!
- It's time to go to bed, it's time to go to bed. You should already have a rest.
-But the rest, he will soon bring me to the grave.
-Well, what are you saying? - Nadenka, you understood perfectly,
what I mean. Besides, I feel wonderful.
We are already finishing with Lev Davidovich.
"Five minutes, Nadezhda Konstantinovna, I swear."
-I rely on your responsibility. -Yes. Come, thank you.
You forced us to open ahead of time.
-Vladimir Ilyich, do not let fear prevail! Yes, Dzerzhinsky
lost, but we have a majority in the Politburo. At the plenum we will
stronger.
-Well, I'll have to count on my authority and your energy.
-Yes. It's time to throw off the masks. "I'll be the first to speak tomorrow,
Stalin - the second, you - the third. I'll strike, I'll knock him out of the saddle.
He can not navigate, improvisation is not his fad,
and mumbles speech. And then you will finish it.
Subjecting him to spanking for the whole party, we will deprive him of his authority forever.
Have you read it? -Short and murderous.
"Yes?
Never felt more alive. Lydia Alexandrovna!
Here, reprint it.
Awful want a fight.
-Switch with Stalin.
- Lev Davidovich, you need an urgent telegram from the Kremlin.
-What's there? Read it.
- Vladimir Ilyich has a stroke. He is paralyzed, can not speak.
The members of the Politburo in your absence decided not to cancel the plenum.
-You can call it anything, but, in my opinion, you have simply lost.
-When you look ahead all the time, there's no time to look back,
and it allows the enemy to hit you in the back.
STOCK IN THE DOOR
What, Natasha? -Courier from the Canadian embassy.
He asks you, he says it's urgent.
-After the attempt, the Mexicans made a request about all the foreigners,
who were here. Jackson is not who he claims to be.
-I'll call security. -Do not...
We knew that this day would someday ...
will come, Natasha.
-I beg you, please ... -It's quiet, quiet.
I made a decision.
It will be better, believe me.
Goodbye.
I love you.
I've always loved only you.
- I know.
I loved you, too.
One of you.
-Continue? -Yes!
After a stroke, Lenin ...
I retired, and very soon I was left alone, as if in a vacuum.
Stalin planted his people everywhere. This new breed of people
with empty eyes, ready to fulfill any will of the leader.
And then it all ended.
-I do not know that the opposition headed by Trotsky led
hooligan bullying against Lenin ...
-Save calm.
-Trotsky can not be a communist, because he is a speculator
in its Jewish nature!
-Is it any wonder that Trotsky is scolding now in vain
one of Lenin's many students-Comrade Stalin?
He does not believe in building socialism in Russia, because he does not believe
by virtue of the Russian people!
-Run shot!
-All is ready! Stop, where did you go ?!
{}
- Dad! Dad!
People! This is Leon Trotsky! This is arbitrary!
Why are you silent, people ?!
-In connection with the fact that Trotsky's activities took on the character of
more and more open counter-revolution, the party is put in necessity
to send him outside the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics.
-Last question. Catch you back ...
-In Russia? -In the past.
Come again to this path, what would you do differently,
where would have turned? -Never where.
-And how are your children, father, friends, comrades-in-arms, millions of victims?
-You did not understand anything.
You cling to the little things. I changed the world.
-No. No!
You dared, but nothing happened. Everything that you did in your life,
brought you here to life in fear and hatred, and will continue to
Only worse. You will rot day after day, convincing yourself,
that you did everything right, but you will not believe it.
You can not be saved even by suicide,
because then you will sign your own defeat.
Farewell, Trotsky. -Jackson!
Remember, I told you that we are from the same test?
Forget it.
You are ... different.
A coward.
You do not have enough will to bring the matter to an end. I'm not talking about the will
go beyond the imposed boundaries. Ask if I want to return ...
I will return necessarily, only not in the past, but in the future.
I threw seeds in the ground and they will ascend. Through pain, blood
I showed people a new world, and they no longer want to live in the old.
Never. I set it on fire, it burns. Can you smell it?
Smell! The smell of burning! The only thing I regret is that I was not
rather cruel and consistent, showed softness where necessary
have a firm hand. I stepped back where I had to go forward,
without regard for any sacrifices. Nothing, this world is on fire
in the flame of a new war. And who knows what it will lead to?
and will your Stalin hold out. I feel the power in me.
I feel the power! I'm ready to return!
This war is a cleansing fire, in which a new,
just peace.
My ideas are immortal, which means that I myself am immortal.