OVER THE SUBTITLES WORKED: O. KULAGIN, Y. KARAVAN, S. ARTEMS, A. PRYAKH
TERRIBLE LAUGHTER
-Sorry, Leiba.
Left
You have a letter.
From Frida.
* It's stange...
What does she want?
"You did not allow me to paint your portrait.
I really miss my Lion. "
FUNNY FOLK MUSIC
"Comrade Trotsky!" Comrade Trotsky! And I'm waiting for you at the first car.
I thought you were comfortable, and you are directly with the people.
Come along.
You stayed in your America, Comrade Trotsky.
The whole revolution passed without you. -Revolution is just beginning.
-Here! And Comrade Lenin said the same thing.
"I'm with you, peasant!" -It's only too bad, not all of our
ideas permeated, Comrade Trotsky. -Your. I'm still non-partisan.
"Here, Comrade Trotsky." Your former and current apartment.
IN ENGLISH: Mom, tell me, why does he look at us like that?
-Serezh, please speak Russian.
"Welcome back, Comrade Trotsky."
-In New York, the Negroes live like that. -After the revolution, no one
will not live, Lyova. -Where's the suitcase?
- Carry that room.
-Hello! Can I see Mr. Trotsky?
-Hospodin asked me not to call.
"Alexander Kerensky would like to meet with you,
Minister and Chairman of the Provisional Government.
"I understand that you are aware of that shaky dual power,
which has now developed in Russia. -As I understand,
The Provisional Government is still subject to the army, the gendarmerie,
The bourgeoisie loves and obeys you, but the working class does not pose a penny.
-Yes, you are absolutely right. The authority of the workers we, frankly,
do not use. And therefore we have not the slightest opportunity to influence
to strikes and stalemate movements. -This possibility exists
only the Soviet of Workers' Deputies. -Facts!
Pretenders, dancing to the tune of this maniacal loon of Lenin, who
he does not think about anything except his own power. That is why any of our
initiatives. The Soviets boycotted and sabotaged.
-I apologize for interrupting you, Alexander Fedorovich.
What do you want from me? -I read some of your works,
Lev Davidovich, and I find you much wiser than Lenin. And wherein
you are no less an authority among the workers.
We would like to enlist your help in order to rein in
strike movement. -The point is that I arrived
not to curb, but to lead a strike movement.
-Listen, Lev Davidovich, we all wanted a revolution. And now, when
the tsar abdicated, Russia has a chance - a chance to go differently,
civilized, European way with democracy and parliamentary
republic. I lived in your Europe as an example
longer than you. I saw their democracy with the parliamentary republics ...
Pszyk is everything. There is no more freedom there than under tsarism.
"So you think unchecked chaos is more just?"
- Do you know what I think?
I ... will sweep your whole world to hell.
I'll take power in Petrograd ...
and finish the revolution. On a global scale.
Even if they tear me in half. And neither with you, nor with anyone else
I'm not going to agree on anything.
- Lord, a moment of attention!
"As a minimum, Leon, one of us certainly does."
-You can? -We both saw my wife naked.
"Do not flatter it, boys. The whole world saw me naked.
-Frank, come in, meet. This is Frida Kahlo and her husband Diego Rivera.
They are not only world famous artists, but also convinced
socialists. -You see, you were not mistaken again, Leon.
-What? -He said that you have not yet outlived
in himself philistine concepts of personal insults, but still run back
in order to finish his business. I'm afraid the Seigneur Trotsky forgot
to mention that I do not put in a penny nine out of ten of his words.
This is the basis for our communication. -How is it?
-I, I think I'll come back another time, when it will not be necessary to support
nobody's shock. -Choose, quit, comrade. let's
send this vicious woman to write a portrait of old Trotsky, and we are with you
Let's drink this ambrosia. Sit down! -No! No, Frida. All this is nowhere
not good. You will not write me in this.
-Leon, but this costume symbolizes a vicious aggression!
Your soul is only bright colors! -I, as a materialist,
I do not believe in any soul. -You just got used to dictating
their conditions. And you never accept strangers.
-Yes! It's always been like this. -That's why you never had
real companions. You could not work together even with Lenin.
-Lenin always envied me and was looking for any opportunity to take me away
from the political field, and do it so as not to compromise
himself before the Bolsheviks.
-But despite the fact that Comrade Trotsky
not Bolshevik, our party intends to
recommend it to the executive committee of the Petrograd Soviet. I want to remind,
that Comrade Trotsky was a member of the Soviet of Workers' Deputies as far back as 1905.
A colossal experience. For many of us, Lev Davidovich almost became
not a symbol of the First Russian Revolution. But the main thing ... The main thing is that he
is extremely authoritative among the working masses, and to neglect such
authority, comrades, on our part it would be at least
unreasonable. So, comrades, I propose to vote. Who for that,
that Comrade Trotsky should join the Executive Committee of the Petrograd Soviet?
Hello
SCHOOL BELL
-You are parrot! -Hose is hunchbacked!
-How much time? -Two Jews.
-Mary Pavlovna, thank you.
-Hello. -No bread.
-Wait, but here's the woman just ...
-It was just. And no more.
"So, comrades, who is against?"
-Serge! Come on, get away from him! - Leo! Seryozha!
-Go away, I told you!
- Where's the cap?
-Thank you, comrades.
-Fuckers Lenin! Smokes incense to me, and his clerks at the same time
they compromise me. Thank you. Afraid that I will take his power from him.
But there is no open conflict, because workers love me.
-The boys were again harassed at the gymnasium.
SPEAK ON GERMAN
I now think: maybe it was not worth contacting the Bolsheviks?
Around so much hatred. -Bolsheviks are popular among workers.
- There are no workers in the gymnasium. There are children of shopkeepers and merchants.
-When I take power, there will be neither shopkeepers nor merchants.
-And bread was not given again today.
You know, Lyova, until everything settles ... Here.
-Tike-so ... -Leon, stop clowning.
Otherwise, I will never finish your portrait. And I do not have much
time. Leon! -When did you start to worry about this?
time? You did not come to write my portrait, did you? True?
"You're a funny man, Rivera." -What do you have in mind?
"I heard that three years ago you sheltered Trotsky at your dacha,
slept with your wife instead of gratitude.
Of course, I do not believe the rumors, but ... -Love, like talent, can not
belong only to man. "So Trotsky betrayed you,
and you bring your woman to him on a date?
- Senor Jackson! You look so serious ...
What are you arguing about? -We discuss with your husband
concept of betrayal. -Ah! ..
-He argues that this is something philistine and almost
not bourgeois. - Very simple, Jackson.
In the absence of private property in a narrow sense and accessibility
all and all things are canceled and the reflexes of the owner.
And therefore, betrayal is impossible. -The world I dream about,
does not abolish the concept of fidelity. -Bravo! Bravo!
-Well, if the term fidelity makes you laugh, but betrayal
you ascribe to bourgeois prejudices, tell us ...
about Nikolay Markin.
- Who is this Markin, Leon? - A man from the past. One of many.
Hello!
So...
Uh-huh.
What do I have to say to this ... I will give you 25 rubles for it.
And if you strongly ask me, then even 26 rubles.
No, I do not argue, you can go to Mendel at Liteiny,
to hear there the price of 22 rubles and again to return to Usharovich.
- Give me the money.
-Hi from the old shtiblet! -Kolya! Why do not you come in?
I already started to be afraid for you. Faya, what are you standing there for? Kolya has come.
"And do not be afraid for us, uncle of the Jew." You know, we are all with honor,
in conscience, in justice.
Everybody is here? - It's exactly like in a drugstore, Kolya.
-Oh well, you can breathe smoothly.
Come on.
-All fear is lost, bastards. -I beg you, Faya. But we have
order on the street. No one will do it the way we did
Feldman with Shpalernaya, who came and was killed. Here are your 26 rubles.
Usharovich never deceives anyone, even when he is robbed.
-Release.
Do not bother, uncle!
Now pick it up.
-Ah, shantrap!
Get lost, do you? - Brothers, brothers! What business?
We can share it. - This is my territory, brother.
STONES
And that trembling knees? Come on, go pick up the money.
Usharovich chew. The second will no longer give. Come on, come on.
-Thank you. -And thank you, you will not be healthy.
Five rubles from you - a brother to take a walk.
Now
-Well, wait a minute.
You ... cho? And this is exactly yours?
You Cho, Trotsky, or what? Brothers, this is ... Trotsky! Here you go.
Sorry friend. I did not recognize you at once. Comrade Trotsky, can I help you?
hand shake? Oh please. Kolya I'm Markin. Leva!
Yes, I'm on your articles grew! You write business, business!
You are my good! How is it there? .. The dictatorship of the proletariat, that everything
in honor, in conscience, in justice, yes?
Only it is bad that you are a Jew.
-After the revolution there will be neither Russians nor Jews ...
Comrade Markin, there will not be.
-And why are you offended? No offense. I did it with love.
Here is a Jew, but such a human!
Come on, you cho. Take it.
You, this, if necessary, you say.
Thank you
-Get off!
What do you mean, do not you understand? Get away from him!
Do not you understand that?
-Well, I do not have a free space. Well, how much to say?
Go ahead.
Hello, Natalia Ivanovna!
You've been missed the last time.
Here you are for past rations and tepericha.
Why did not you immediately say that you are leading your friendship with Nikolai Grigorievich?
-Kronstadt revolutionary sailors
express full trust
Comrade Trotsky.
And we demand that the hero of 1905 become a member of the Petrograd Soviet
workers and peasants' deputies.
Who is for making Lev Davidovich Trotsky
member of the Petrograd Soviet?
Thank you.
-I can not even look, as you shake hands with Lenin.
- In politics, Natasha, do not make sharp movements.
Lenin is the head of the Bolsheviks. To get his people,
I should not quarrel with him. -And then you are not a Bolshevik yourself?
-Rano, Bolivars can not stand two. -What?
1: Bring it on!
First I discredit Lenin, then I'll take his place
at the helm of the party. -It is interesting for you, for politicians.
Everything is like in dogs: at first the asses are sniffed at each other, and then the throats are torn.
And what did not you share with Lenin? He's like a normal guy.
-Peace. The whole world.
-You are in charge of one of the last battle-worthy units of the Russian army,
Mr. Kornilov. In times of general panic and retreat
you manage not only to keep your front line, but also to take prisoners
Austro-Hungarians. -Good to serve the Fatherland.
"I want to make you a Minister of War." Ask for so many parts,
as you see fit. The main thing is to stop this fucking Germanic
offensive. -You are a bully, Mr. liberal.
But who has allowed this situation? I'll tell you: it's you,
cabinet clean, not wishing to dirty gloves.
-Don't bend the stick. I am a representative of civil authority,
but the problem is with you in the army. -Please, I'll show you yours.
civil power. Kindly see: the agitator of the Bolsheviks,
party that you in Petrograd not only tolerate, but also admit
to printing machines. And here is what he gave to the soldiers. Admire.
"There is no German and Russian, there is a worker exploiter." Let's drop the rifles,
we'll shoot at the officers, not each other. "
-But with this in my head, my people go into battle. And you from your fucking
liberalism does not even try to prevent it.
-I just do not want to plunge the country into bloody chaos.
Fire
-The only way to avoid chaos now is to do just that.
I am ready to accept your offer, but with the condition that
in Petrograd, once and for all you will get rid of Bolshevik filth,
which breaks up my army from the inside. -You're right. Bolsheviks can not
to admit to power. I wait for the first legal reason and ...
- Spit on legality. If this continues to appear among my soldiers,
by my honor, I'll leave the front and advance to Petrograd,
to personally hang out on the pillars first of those who print this,
and then those who can do this. I have the honor.
- Join the Bolshevik Party! Only the Bolsheviks have a clear
Event schedule
"Well, are you really going to the Bolsheviks?"
-You must pay tribute to Lenin, such a path from hatred to the love of the people.
Whom I see! -Dad mom! Imagine,
Uncle Kolya drove us to the shooting gallery! -And I shot from targets on targets.
-Well done. Give them money, let them buy something.
Thank you
-Greet Jews from the sailors of the Baltic! "Comrade Markin, I really appreciate all that,
what do you do for us, but if I ask you to pick up the children from the gymnasium,
it means taking them out of the gymnasium, and not shooting them with a revolver.
-You cho, hit the tail hit? Well gave your boys the powder to smell.
And what? Who does not know how to handle weapons, is he a man?
-I can not handle. Am I not a man? It's just not included
in the sphere of my vital interests. - Leva, do not get stuck.
-Don't worry so much. Well, you do not know how, I'll teach you. Lord, it's something.
- Get your hands off that.
Ok, I have to go. -I'm with you?
-No, he's just impenetrable. Natalya spend with the guys to the house.
-I did not say something, did I?
-Do you go home?
- Join the Bolshevik Party! Only the Bolsheviks have
clear program!
-Where are you from, Kolya? -We are? From Penza.
The village of Russian Syromyas. Not, but cho? From the river went - she, too
Syromyas is called. And there is also the Tatar Syromyas. Yes.
So there in general: 1st Syromyasskaya, 2nd Syromyasskaya, 3rd Syromyasskaya.
Do not get lost, in short. -Oh!
Wait, but Penza is far from the sea. How did you get into the fleet?
-So who asked me? Called, and that's all. Well, me
like. I like the storm.
Before that he worked in the food industry. Do not believe me, I got drunk off of boredom.
-Well, what do not you believe? I will.
-Who is the last one, the bourgeois.
Well, thank you for spending. -Let me straight to the front door.
-No no need. Next we ourselves. Thank you, Kolya.
- Comrade Trotsky. -Yes.
-I do not understand you. -What exactly do not you understand?
- Specifically, we do not understand what you are doing in the revolution.
We are building a just peace for the workers and peasants. And you?
You're an intellectual. -Vladimir Ulyanov-Lenin
also an intellectual. What does it change? -No, you're confused, Trotsky.
Lenin is like an icon in a world without God.
And which one of you is the icon? You're a Jew.
-We will build a new world. For all.
-No. We do not build for everyone.
-Lev! And I wanted to go home, and then I think I'll wait for you.
Here, I waited.
You do not have to be angry with me, eh? If cho. My tongue is so bad.
I always say first, and then I think that's where it's going.
I'm a slow mind, after all. Leva, but to you with all my heart, do you hear?
Well, it's true.
Let's have a drink?
You know, you can think whatever you want there, but you're all different to me.
Though he is a Jew. And I'll tear your throats for you, so that, in honor,
on conscience ... -Hair. I know.
I, Nikolay, will need your help soon. Yours and your guys
in Kronstadt. "It's not a question, Leva, my brother."
Than I can - I will help! Be.
"Comrades, the Red Kronstadters, the bourgeois ministers are dragging Russia
in the swamp of war, our comrades are arrested and sent to the Crosses.
Meanwhile, the people's situation is no better than under the Bloody Nikolashka.
Correctly? CHOROM: That's right!
-How much will we endure it? - To hell with the ministers!
-Give the power of the Bolsheviks! - Long live the red Kronstadt,
glory and pride of the revolution! -Oh, brother, go to Peter!
Let's show the bourgeois who is in charge! - Go and make yourself listen!
-Short to endure! Long live Lenin!
Long live the Bolshevik Party!
Let's free our brothers from prisons!
Aida, brothers!
-Shtyk, what has become of it?
"Alekseich, run away!"
-Citizens are prisoners, will!
-What do you mean, let all the prisoners go?
Find out who is behind this.
It is clear.
-You are a legitimate reason.
Urgently write the order. For the attempt of the state
coup immediately arrest all the leaders of the Bolsheviks.
And first of all - Lenin.
-Last news! The rebellion of sailors is crushed by the Cossacks!
All the leaders of the Bolsheviks fled the city!
Last news! All the leaders of the Bolsheviks fled the city!
- So you did not go to bed?
-Have you packed your suitcase? -Aha.
Don't be scared . . .
-How it became known to us, this vile provocation was planned
the Bolshevik Party. Fortunately, we managed to stop this sneaky blow
in the back. I issued a decree on the immediate arrest of all the leaders
Bolsheviks. However, they fled cowardly, including their leader
Ulyanov-Lenin. In this regard, I want to state the following ...
- I need your attention. As you know, I never concealed my
sympathy for the ideas of the Bolshevik Party.
And now, when its leaders threw hundreds of thousands of workers, soldiers,
sailors who believed them, I can not stand aside and ask
me a Bolshevik.
-What should we do? -He leaves us no choice.
-I publicly declare that I participated in the preparation of yesterday's
events. I do not regret anything and do not intend to flee.
"In that case, Mr. Trotsky, you must be detained." Arrest him!
-Peroda will be for us, because the truth is behind us.
-Trotsky is the hero of the revolution! -Correctly.
SCANDE: Trotsky! Trotsky!
- Natasha, everything will be fine.
I love you.
The phone rings.
"It's great that you dealt with the Bolsheviks, Mr. Kerensky.
Let everyone leave, arresting only one? Yes, and he is alive and well.
-You can not imagine what will begin if he is shot.
Besides ... - I do not care!
If today he will not be shot by the evening, I am speaking in Petrograd.
And I'll put you on the wall next to him.
-Well, Khan, you, zhdydara. I thought you were warming up here and after a month or two
Kerensky will set you free? No. General Kornilov goes to the city.
Here he is you, dogs, just will not be sorry. And you first on the lamp
the column will hang.
Laughs.)
-Natasha ... I mean Natalia Ivanovna, no one expected this.
- Can not you think of anything? -So, Natalia Ivanovna, understand,
now the Cossack regiment is guarding the prison.
"Kolya, I'm asking you, please, come up with something."
Help me! For my sake, please!
-That's it! Basta.
Do not go out of the house.
If I do not come back, leave town.
Today. All.
Great, guys!
What are serious?
Severe. I have a question for the eldest. To the eldest. One question!
-This is the residence of the chairman of the Provisional Government.
- Yes you that! I will not let you go without a special permit.
-A, special pass, right? I had it somewhere. Now.
But where? Oh, by the way, noble boots!
Well then you! Well, neater!
{}{Stop!
-Muzhiki, what are you? A?
Are you guys? -What's going on here?
-Yes, I tried to break through. - So arrest him.
-It is possible and so, only I need to tell you the news
from General Kornilov.
-Skip.
"My mind is not very quick, Comrade Kerensky."
-Take off.
-That's the matter of your seams, and I understand. Yes, you yourself know.
There's a gray face. You probably do not sleep well at night, do you?
"Let's get to the point." -Yes, where is closer?
Kornilov will not be in the city today or tomorrow. First the Bolsheviks
will pull up, and then you.
Let Trotsky go - and I will help you save your skin.
-And you know that your Trotsky demands not only to let him go,
but also to arm the workers? -Of course! And who against Kornilov
will go? Army? Yes, not in life!
Everything is simple, Comrade Kerensky. To unite the workers against Kornilov
can only Bolsheviks. And now in the city from the Bolsheviks
only Trotsky.
-Oh well. Which you can give guarantees that if I give
your workers a weapon, they will not turn it against the government?
-No.
CROWD LIKE
-... manager was in the shop. A man - well ... a clean bear.
Excuse me. As a pack zasunet ... In the sense of a person hit - immediately
birds of paradise in the eyes. So, in the war, his hand was torn off.
German mine, to the very elbow. -God, what horror!
-Oh nothing. He came back and made himself a new one! Yes, wooden.
They say that he learned to grumble ... in the sense of hammering this hand
no worse than this. And since he was nothing like a peasant, his ...
- Leo!
- So they still had sex?
- I do not care. I am for freedom for all and in everything.
And it's not just words, Jackson.
And then Kornilov never reached Petrograd.
Thanks to Kerensky's cowardice and the mediation of Markin
was at the head of the working army in five thousand bayonets.
- Is this Frida?
-This is a revolution ... and they are.
And they part.
They leave, but they continue to love each other.
-Leva, I need to talk to you. -How interesting.
-I want you to take my words seriously.
-I'm very serious. -Lev ...
Trotsky as a legend is immortal, but not you.
I have money, I can make you new documents and take you away
A place where no one will ever find you.
Your Natalya we can take with us. -Why all share me
and the legend of Trotsky?
There is no one without the other. No.
Running with you, I will first of all betray myself,
but not some fairy-tale character.
-But you yourself said that betrayal is prejudice.
-No, I did not say that.
I said that in the world I always dreamed of, there will be no place
betrayal. But we live in this world.
-There, ahead, White's heels are already shining. And right along the shore -
barn. Long, fathoms a hundred.
My eagles stretched out and past the barn, let's run two by two.
Comrades!
So I say: we run past this barn, and there ...
"Why are you silent, Comrade Fedotov?"
Go on.
-So I say ...
Runs, we mean, and there ... -And there? ..
Four machine-gun calculations of the enemy.
So ... Comrade Rakinsky?
-So, Mrs. ...
... a friend of the pre-war council.
-The whites left four machine guns in the barn. Your platoon, Fedotov,
they had to mow like grass.
-Let me notice, Lev Davidovich, the machine-gunners of the enemy from performing
The combat mission was abandoned, they did not shoot.
- And they came to you with their hands up.
-Yes sir. Having expressed the intention to move to the side ...
"But they came to you, not to Fedotov?"
I asked a question.
-So, of course! Come to me.
-He was a royal officer, a military specialist, in whose devotion
you all doubted, inspects the barn, does everything that is required
were done by you, Fedotov. Your dashing stupidity, arrogance,
negligence could cost the lives of all your soldiers.
THE DOOR OPENED
-So! Opa! In the give, devils!
How cannons kokoshit enemy - so Markin, and as a victory to celebrate -
so without Markin? Hold it!
Oh, Lyova-Lyova, you're my head, golden, curly!
The plan is what he came up with!
Cannon the guns!
I, muzhiks, when I saw him for the first time ...
- Comrades!
Offering a drink.
Let's drink to the heroes who did not live up to that time.
-Oh, head, Lyova! Oh, my head!
Lyova! Where are you going?
- An urgent dispatch. "Moscow, to Lenin.
Intends to develop success,
attack the garrison near Drunken Bora,
by preliminary liquidating coastal artillery by a sabotage group
under the command of ... Markina. Trotsky. "
Send immediately.
-The comrade of the pre-war council, the line is unreliable, my ciphers are old.
If the telegram is intercepted, then for Markin this is a sure death.
-Sent me.
What do you want?
Why did you come?
-What are you doing to me, brother? I did not have anything
with Natalia. And could not be.
-Why what does Natalya have to do with it?
I never went down to jealousy.
-So why? -Why?
We met at the time of my humiliation, the most powerful in life.
You saw me pathetic and remembered this: a frightened intellectual
with trembling knees, which must be protected, guarded,
which you can slap on the shoulder. And I was the chairman
Revolutionary Military Council! A sacred deity!
A demon that everyone was afraid of, except for you.
-What's the difference? I was your friend.
-No.
You made me human, but it was impossible, you can not.
Humanity never wins in wars, only loses.
- Be healthy, brotherly.